魔戒1：魔戒再现 加长版
The.Lord.of.the.Rings:The.Fellowship.of.the.Ring Extended.Edition
字幕校对：绝地幻影(lecozx)
这世界改变了
我从水中触摸到
我从地上感觉到
我从空气中嗅到
过去的一切
都已失落
现在没有人记得了
这一切都从铸造魔戒开始
精灵族得到三只戒指
他们能够长生不老 也是最有智慧、最公平的种族
矮人族分到七只戒指
他们很会挖掘矿坑 是山洞的巧心工匠
而人类…
则分到九只戒指
他们比别人更贪图权力
中土世界
每只戒指都拥有 统治每个种族的力量
但他们都受到欺骗
因为还铸造了另一只
魔多
在魔多末日火山的烈焰中
黑暗魔君索伦 暗中铸造了可以奴役世界的…
至尊魔戒
他在至尊魔戒中 注入他的邪恶、残酷
以及统治天下的可怕欲望
一只驾驭一切的至尊魔戒
一个接一个
中土世界的自由之土 感受到至尊魔戒的力量
但是有些人群起反抗
组成了精灵和人类的最后同盟 对抗魔多的邪恶兵团
他们在险恶的末日火山 为中土世界的自由奋战
胜利终于在望
但是至尊魔戒的力量
无人能敌
就在这时候
当大家都失去希望之际
人皇之子埃西铎 拾起他父亲的宝剑
黑暗魔君索伦, 中土世界 自由人民之敌终于被击败
至尊魔戒落入埃西铎手中
他只有一次机会永远摧毁邪恶
但是人心
很容易受到蛊惑
而且至尊魔戒力量不受到控制
它背叛了埃西铎
最后害死了他
不该被遗忘的东西
也遗失了
历史成为传说
传说成为神话
两千五百年来
至尊魔戒的下落无人得知
命运巧妙的安排
让它蛊惑一个新的持有者
我的宝贝
至尊魔戒落入咕鲁手中
他把它带到迷雾山脉的洞穴中
他的身心完全被魔戒占据
它落到我手中
这是我的, 我的爱, 是我的
我的宝贝
它让咕鲁得到违反自然的长寿
五百年来它扭曲他的心智
它在咕鲁阴暗的洞穴中 静静地等待
黑暗再度笼罩大地
谣传东方升起邪恶力量
人们心中产生无比的恐惧
于是至尊魔戒知道
它即将再度现身
它舍弃了咕鲁
但是出乎至尊魔戒的意料之外
它被一个料想不到的人捡到
这是什么?
一个哈比人
夏尔的比尔博巴金斯
一只戒指
不见了!
我的宝贝不见了!
不久的将来
哈比人将决定世界的命运
瑞文戴尔
1400 年
9 月 22 日
哈比屯
以夏尔历法计算
夏尔
哈比屯西区, 巴榭路, 袋底洞
伊利雅德
夏尔
中土世界
世界第三纪元
"去而复返:
哈比人的故事"
比尔博巴金斯著
"去而复返: 哈比人的故事" 比尔博巴金斯著
现在…
该从何说起呢?
是了
"关于…
关于哈比人
…哈比人"
哈比人一直都在夏尔的四区 开恳种植、安居乐业
数百年来
都乐于受到世人遗忘
也就是世上的其他人种
毕竟中土世界充满 不计其数的奇怪生物
哈比人的存在微不足道
他们并非骁勇善战的武士
也不算是聪明绝顶的智者
佛罗多, 有人在敲门
老实说, 有人说
哈比人唯一的热爱就是食物
但这是很不公平的说法
因为我们也很喜欢酿啤酒
和抽烟草
但是我们真正的最爱
就是和平宁静
还有肥沃的土地
每一个哈比人都热爱 从土里长出来的东西
别人一定会觉得 我们的日子过得太悠闲
但是今天更是印证了我的想法
能过朴实简单的生活 真的是一种幸福
生日快乐 比尔博巴金斯
佛罗多, 快去开门
讨厌, 那小子呢?
佛罗多
外面风景多美丽
我要踏上这旅程
眼前道路无止尽
蜿蜒崎岖又漫长
虽然路程尚遥远
－我必须继续前进 －你迟到了
巫师绝对不会迟到 佛罗多巴金斯
也不会早到 他一定是按照计划准时到
见到你真好, 甘道夫
我怎么会错过 你比尔博叔叔的生日?
那老不死还好吧?
听说生日宴会非常盛大
你也知道比尔博 他把这儿搞得鸡飞狗跳
这样他应该高兴了
夏尔有一半人都被邀请
另外一半也不请自来
夏尔的哈比人 如往常一样过着日子
从古到今都一样
自给自足、快乐幸福 没有什么太大的改变
也许也不会有所改变
因为夏尔的一切历久弥新
一代一代地传下去
巴金斯家族一直 都有成员住在山丘下的…
袋底洞
以后也一定会有
不过说实话 最近比尔博有点怪
跟以前比起来更古怪
他成天把自己关在书房
我每次趁他不注意偷看 都看到他总是在研究地图
它跑哪儿去了?
他一定在搞什么名堂
－好吧, 你不说拉倒 －什么?
我知道你一定脱不了关系
真是的
在你出现前 巴金斯家族一向都很规矩
这倒是真的
我们从不冒险或犯规
如果你指的是那只恶龙 那件事与我无关
我只是推了你叔叔一把
不管怎样 你都正式被列为捣乱份子
真的吗?
甘道夫! 甘道夫!
放烟火, 甘道夫
－甘道夫 －放烟火, 甘道夫
甘道夫?
－你回来了, 我好高兴 －我也是, 好孩子
我也是
不要, 多谢了
我不欢迎访客、祝寿者或远亲
那么一个老朋友呢?
甘道夫?
－比尔博巴金斯 －甘道夫老友
见到你真好 111 岁大寿, 谁会相信?
你一点都没老
进来吧
欢迎
来吧
喝杯茶? 或是小酌两杯?
我还有几瓶 1296 年的陈年好酒
很好的年份, 几乎跟我一样老
我老爸珍藏的, 开一瓶如何?
我喝茶就好, 谢谢
你上礼拜就该到了
你一向都想来就来、就走就走
只是我有点措手不及 家里只有冻鸡和腌黄瓜
还有乳酪, 不行, 太寒酸了
我有覆盆子果酱、苹果馅饼
但是好像还不太够 哦, 不, 我没问题
我找到一些海绵蛋糕
孤山
我可以煮几个蛋…
－茶就行了, 谢谢 －好吧
－你介意我吃吗? －你尽管吃吧
比尔博巴金斯
说我不在家
塞克维尔巴金斯
－我知道你在家 －他们在打我房子的主意
我这么老不死 他们一直都不原谅我
我被这些像苍蝇 成天黏著我的亲戚
吵得一刻不得安宁
我好想再看到高耸的山脉
然后找一个安静的地方写书 啊, 茶滚了
－你真的要实现你的计划? －对, 一切都在计划中
我全都安排好了
谢谢你
佛罗多起了疑心
当然了 他可是巴金斯家的人
不是硬瓶家的笨小孩
你会告诉他吧?
－你会告诉他吧? －他很喜欢你
我知道
我开口的话他一定会跟我去
但他还是衷心深爱夏尔的家园
绿油油的树林和草地
潺潺的溪流
我老了, 甘道夫
虽然我看起来并不老 但是我的心老了
我的意志变得很薄弱
一切都索然无味
就像面包上的牛油涂得不够多
我需要一个很长的假期
我并不打算回来
我打定主意不回来
老托比种的 南区最好的烟草
甘道夫老友
这将是令人难忘的一晚
你好
小胖博哲 很高兴见到你, 欢迎
山姆, 快去邀萝丝跳舞
－我想再喝一杯啤酒 －不行啦
去呀
我站在那儿
面对三个可怕的食人妖
它们吵著…
要怎么把我们煮来吃
是一口就把我们给吞了 或是一个接著一个把我们压扁
他们喋喋不休吵个没完没了
结果天亮的第一道曙光
把它们都变成石头
快点
飞走了
最大的那个啦
抱腹太太, 很高兴见到你 欢迎, 欢迎
这都是你的小孩吗?
老天爷, 你还真能生呀
比尔博?
塞克维尔巴金斯
快躲起来
谢了, 好侄子
你真是个好孩子, 佛罗多
我一直都很自私
我真的很自私自利
你爸妈死后我收养了你 不过并不是出于好心
我想是因为…
在这么多亲戚里头
只有你有一种冒险的精神
比尔博, 你是不是 偷喝了老爹自己酿的啤酒?
没有
但是这并不重要
重要的是…
你一定会过得很好
－插好了 －你应该把它插在地上
－插好了呀 －要插在外面啦
这都是你的馊主意
比尔博
当心那只飞龙
这儿有一千年没出现飞龙了
－这儿有一千年没出现飞龙了 －再来一次
梅里亚达克.烈酒鹿 和彼利坚.图克
我就知道
致词, 比尔博
致词!
亲爱的巴金斯家和波芬家
图克家和烈酒鹿家
葛卢伯家、丘伯家
吹号者家
博哲家
抱腹家
－和傲脚家 －是傲足啦
今天是我 111 岁生 日
生日快乐
但是 111 年的时光太短了 我真想多跟你们在一起
这么杰出优秀的哈比人
我只认识你们一丁点
而你们一丁点也不值得我喜欢
我要做一件事
这件事我拖了太久
很遗憾我要宣布宴会结束了
我要走了
我要向大家道别
再见
你一定觉得这招很高明
你没看到他们的表情吗?
世上有很多神奇戒指 但是不该随便乱用
我只是开个玩笑
不过就像平常一样, 你说的对
－你会照顾佛罗多吧? －当然会
我会好好照顾他
－我要把一切都留给他 －那只戒指呢?
－那也要留下来吗? －当然
我用信封装好放在壁炉上面
不对, 等一下…
它在我的口袋
真奇怪, 不是吗?
是呀, 有何不可呢?
－我何不留著它? －你应该把戒指留下来
有这么困难吗?
没有呀
当然有
现在我突然不想把它给别人
它是我的, 是我找到的
－你也没必要动肝火吧 －这全是你的错
它是我的
我一个人的
－我的宝贝 －宝贝?
以前也有别人这么叫过它
这是我的戒指, 与你无关
那只戒指你留着够久了
－你只想独吞它 －比尔博巴金斯!
别把我当成一个江湖术士
我并不想抢你的东西
我只想帮助你
我们都认识这么久了
请你像以前一样相信我
放手吧
你说得对
戒指一定要留给佛罗多
天色晚了, 路还很长
是时候了
比尔博
戒指还在你的口袋
我替我的书想到一个结尾
"他从此快乐地生活下去 直到他寿终正寝"
你一定会的, 老友
再见了, 甘道夫
再见了, 比尔博
眼前道路无止尽…
后会有期了
它是我的, 我一个人的
我的宝贝
黑暗中的谜语
比尔博
我的宝贝
宝贝
他走了, 对吧?
他一直都说要离开这儿
没想到他真的走了
甘道夫?
比尔博的戒指
他去和精灵住在一起
他把袋底洞留给你
还有他所有的财产
戒指是你的了
－把它藏起来 －你要去哪儿?
－我一定要去办些事 －什么事?
－我有一些疑问一定要得到解答 －你才刚到
我不明白
我也不明白
你要保密
把它藏起来
夏尔!
巴金斯!
"第二纪元的 3434 年
以下是埃西铎的记载 刚铎之王…
以及找到至尊魔戒的过程"
"我终于拿到手了
这只至尊魔戒 将是我的镇国之宝
我的后代将永远对它效忠
我绝不容许魔戒受到任何损伤
这是我的宝贝
我经过多少痛苦才得到它
戒环的刻痕逐渐褪色
那些赤焰般的文字 现在全部消失
只有火焰能让秘密显现"
夏尔
巴金斯
巴金斯家族都住在哈比屯
在那边
我的身心已疲惫
阵阵风雨不停歇
但是我仍有…
好长的路要走
雨滴声音多美妙
大珠小珠落玉盘
不管雨水或清泉
都比不上这儿的啤酒
最近有一些陌生人经过夏尔
包括矮人族和更可怕的坏人
一场大战即将来临
山里头来了一群妖魔鬼怪
这些只是谣传或是 小孩子的童言童语而已
你越来越像比尔博巴斯金 别跟他一样疯言疯语
佛罗多先生, 你叔叔是有点疯
我以他为荣
－干杯, 老爹 －干杯
夏尔以外的事跟我们无关
你们只要不去惹麻烦 麻烦就不会找上门
－晚安了, 小伙子 －晚安
晚安了, 美丽的姑娘
他最好别打她的主意
放心啦, 山姆 萝丝知道他是个浑人
真的吗?
－晚安, 山姆 －晚安, 佛罗多先生
你有守密吗? 它安全吗?
你在做什么?
把手伸出来
很冰凉
你看到什么?
你看到什么吗?
没有
什么也没有
等等
上面有刻痕
好像是精灵文, 我看不懂
很少人看得懂
这是魔多的古文字 我现在不能念出来
魔多!
它说的是
"至尊戒, 驭众戒
至尊戒, 寻众戒
魔戒至尊引众戒
禁锢众戒黑暗中"
这只至尊魔戒
是黑暗魔君索伦 用末日火山的烈焰铸成
埃西铎从索伦手中夺过来
比尔博找到它
－在咕鲁的洞穴中 －是的
比尔博六十年来 不动声色持有至尊魔戒
他因此而延长了寿命 延迟了老化
但是状况已经改变了 邪恶在魔多蠢蠢欲动
至尊魔戒被唤醒了
它听到主人的召唤
但是索伦已经被消灭了
不, 佛罗多
索伦的灵魂没有死
他的生命和至尊魔戒紧紧相系
至尊魔戒仍然幸存
他的半兽人大军与日俱增
他在魔多也重建了要塞巴拉多
索伦只要得到至尊魔戒 就能让黑暗再度笼罩大地
他在搜寻至尊魔戒
全心全意、不择手段地搜寻
同时至尊魔戒也渴望
回到它主人的手中
他们本为一体
至尊魔戒和黑暗魔君
佛罗多
绝对不能让他找到至尊魔戒
好
那就把它藏起来再也不提
没人知道它在这儿, 是吧?
是不是? 甘道夫
有一个人知道 比尔博得到至尊魔戒
我到处在找咕鲁
但是魔君先找到他
他不晓得被拷打了多久
但是在可怕的哀嚎和呻吟声中 他们听出两个名字:
夏尔
巴金斯
巴金斯 他们会找到这里来
什么人?
你拿去, 甘道夫
－拿去 －不行
－你一定要拿去 －你不能把魔戒给我
－我要把它给你 －别引诱我, 佛罗多
我不敢拿
我更不能保护它
你要了解
我只希望利用至尊魔戒行善事
但是它透过我 将释放无法想像的邪恶力量
－它不能留在这儿 －没错
的确不能
我该怎么做?
－你一定要尽快离开 －我该去哪里?
离开这儿, 赶到布理村
布理
－那你呢? －我会等你
在跃马旅店
－魔戒在那儿安全吗? －我不知道, 佛罗多
我无法回答你
我必须去见巫师长 他有智慧及力量, 相信我
他知道该怎么做
你不能用巴金斯这名字
这名字在夏尔之外不安全
白天赶路, 别走大道
我可以穿过农田
好孩子
哈比人真不可思议
只要一个月 就能了解他们
但一百年后
他们仍然让你吃惊不已
趴下来
可恶的山姆卫斯詹吉 你一直在偷听吗?
我才没有偷听什么 我只是在窗外除草而已
现在除草未免太晚了
－我听到说话声 －你听到什么? 快说
没什么啦
我听到戒指 黑暗魔君和世界末日
甘道夫大爷, 别伤害我 别把我变成死的东西
不要吗?
也许不会
你有更好的用处
快点, 山姆, 跟上来
你们千万要小心
敌人有很多眼线
包括飞鸟野兽
魔戒呢?
千万别戴上它
黑暗魔君的爪牙会被吸引来
你要记住
至尊魔戒想要回到主人手上
它想要被找到 就是这样
这是什么?
我只要再跨一步
就是我离家最远的一次
走吧, 山姆
我记得比尔博总是说 :
－"旅行很危险" －"一旦你出了门上了路
如果你不专心看路
谁晓得你会被带到哪里去"
山姆
木精灵
他们要去净白塔以外的港口
他们要去灰港岸
他们要离开中土世界
永远不再回来
我不知道为什么
我会感到这么悲伤
地上到处都是盘根错节 把我的背顶得好疼
闭上眼睛
想像你躺在自己的床上
舒服的床垫和柔软的羽毛枕头
这没有用, 佛罗多
我在荒郊野外永远都睡不著
我也睡不著
末日火山再度升起烟硝
时间不多了
灰袍巫师甘道夫赶到艾辛格
寻求我的建议
你就是为了这件事来找我?
我的老友
萨鲁曼
－你能确定吗? －千真万确
至尊魔戒被发现了?
它这么多年来一直在夏尔
－就在我眼前 －你却没有看到它
半身人的烟草熏坏了你的眼睛
但是还来得及 还有时间对抗索伦的势力
时间?
我们哪来的时间?
索伦的力量几乎完全恢复
虽然他尚未完全转生
但他的灵魂仍有强大魔力
虽然他被封在要塞中 但是他却无所不知
他的视线能穿透乌云、阴影 土地甚至 肉体
你知道我在说什么吗?
一个被烈焰包围的 巨大眼睛
就是索伦之眼
他正在聚集邪恶力量
很快就能召集大军 向中土世界展开攻击
你知道这些?
怎么会?
我亲眼看到
真知晶球也是个危险的工具 萨鲁曼
为什么?
为什么要害怕使用它?
其它的真知之石下落不明
我们不知道有谁也在看
时间来不及了
索伦的行动已经展开
那九个已经离开米那斯魔窟
那九个?
他们在仲夏夜跨越艾辛河
伪装成黑骑士
－他们已经到了夏尔? －他们会找到至尊魔戒
然后杀死它的持有者
佛罗多
你以为哈比人能对抗索伦吗?
谁都无法抗拒他
没有人能对抗
魔多的力量
我们必须加入他们
我们必须投靠索伦
这么做才聪明, 朋友
告诉我…
朋友
智者萨鲁曼几时发疯了?
我给你机会
自愿帮助我
但是你却宁愿选择受苦
佛罗多先生
佛罗多?
－我以为我把你跟丢了 －你在说什么?
－甘道夫跟我说过 －他说什么?
"紧跟着他, 山姆卫斯詹吉" 我会紧跟着你不放
我们还在夏尔, 会有什么事?
佛罗多
－梅里, 是佛罗多巴金斯 －哈啰, 佛罗多
快起来
起来, 佛罗多
这算什么?
你们偷摘老农夫马嘎的菜
你们快给我滚
快滚, 臭小子
你们最好小心点 别让我抓到
生什么气嘛, 只是两根红萝卜
还有几棵包心菜
和上礼拜偷的几袋马铃薯
－还有上上礼拜偷的蘑菇 －皮聘, 重点是…
他太小题大作了
快跑
好险哦
我好像摔断了什么
烈酒鹿和图克家最会惹麻烦
什么? 这是一条捷径耶
－去哪儿的捷径? －蘑菇
那是我的
好大一朵哦, 梅里
这里也有, 山姆
我们最好躲起来
躲起来
快点
别出声
那是什么东西?
你看到什么吗?
没有
这是怎么回事?
黑骑士在找什么东西 或是什么人
佛罗多
趴下来
我一定要离开夏尔
我跟山姆要赶到布理
没问题
巴寇伯理渡口, 跟我来
快跑
这边, 跟上来
快去松绳
佛罗多
快跑呀, 佛罗多
－快跑 －快点
快跑, 佛罗多
－快点 －快跳
－最近的渡桥有多远? －烈酒桥, 二十哩
来吧
－你们要什么? －我们要去跃马旅店
哈比人, 四个哈比人
－你们来布理有什么事? －我们只是想住旅店
我们的事你管不着
好吧, 我不是故意找茬
天黑后我就得多问一下
听说附近有怪人游荡
小心一点比较好
让开, 小心看路
跃马旅店
对不起
小客人们晚安
如果你们想住一宿 我们有哈比人住的舒适房间
包君满意, 请问大名是…?
山下, 我叫山下
－山下 －我们是灰袍巫师甘道夫的朋友
－你能告诉他我们来了吗? －甘道夫?
甘道夫
是了
我记得了, 一个老头子
长长的灰胡子, 尖尖的帽子
半年没见到他了
现在怎么办?
山姆
他一定会来的
让开
那是什么?
这就是一品脱啤酒
有这么大杯的?
－我也要来一杯 －你已经有一杯了
我们来了之后那个人一直看你
请问一下
坐在角落的那个人是谁?
他是一个游侠 他们很危险, 成天在荒野游荡
我不知道他的名字 但是这儿的人都叫他神行客
神行客
巴金斯
巴金斯? 我认识呀
他就在那儿, 佛罗多巴金斯
我是他表哥
算是远房亲戚啦
－皮聘 －小心点
你躲不了的
我看得见你
在虚空中…
没有生命
只有…
死亡
你太惹人注意了, 山下大爷
你要什么?
我要你小心点你 戴的不是小玩意
－我什么也没戴 －才怪
有必要我也能不被看到
但是完全隐形却不是件易事
－你是谁 －你害怕吗?
害怕
恐怕还不够, 我知道谁在找你
放开他, 否则我让你好看 长腿人
小哈比人, 你很有胆量 但是这救不了你
你不能再等巫师了
他们来了
他们是什么东西?
他们曾经是人类
人类伟大的国王
但是索伦给他们九只魔戒
他们利欲熏心毫不怀疑地收下
结果都沉沦于黑暗力量
成为黑暗魔君的奴隶
他们是戒灵
介于生与死之间
他们随时感受到…
魔戒的存在…
被至尊魔戒吸引着 他们会一直追杀你
－你要带我们去哪儿? －荒野
你怎么知道他是甘道夫的朋友?
我觉得敌人的爪牙 一定会面带微笑
－但是骨子里却很凶恶 －他已经够凶恶了
没办法, 只能相信他
－他要带我们去哪里? －瑞文戴尔, 詹吉大爷
－精灵的家 －你们听到吗? 瑞文戴尔
我们要去见精灵
－各位, 天黑才能歇脚 －那早餐怎么办?
－你们吃过了 －才吃过一顿
第二顿早餐呢?
他不知道有第二顿早餐
早午餐呢? 午餐? 下午茶? 晚餐? 宵夜?
－他应该知道吧 －我看不见得
皮聘
他们在没有哈比人的时候 都吃些什么呢?
她是谁?
你歌曲中形容的女子
露西安
一个嫁给凡人贝伦的女精灵
她后来怎么了?
她死了
快睡吧, 佛罗多
艾辛格听您的命令
黑暗魔君索伦
替我在魔多建立一支大军
主人, 魔多有什么命令? 魔眼有什么吩咐?
我们有很多事要做
这些树非常坚韧, 树根很深
把它们全都拉倒
这是风云顶瞭望台
今晚在这里过夜
这些给你们, 一定要随身佩带
我到处看一下
别乱跑
我的番茄熟了
我要培根
吃番茄吧
－你们在干嘛? －煎番茄、香肠和培根
－我替你留了一些 －笨蛋, 快把火熄掉
－快熄掉 －这下可好了, 番茄上都是灰
快走
退后, 你这恶魔
佛罗多
山姆
神行客
－快救救他 －他被魔窟剑刺中
我救不了他, 精灵才有办法
快点
还有六天行程, 他撑不下去
你要撑下去
甘道夫!
你看, 这是被比尔博变成石头的食人妖
佛罗多先生? 他好冰冷
他会死吗?
他正在进入幽界 很快也会成为死灵
－他们就在附近 －山姆, 你知道阿夕拉斯草吗?
－阿夕拉斯? －又叫王者之剑
那是一种草药
它能阻缓毒性发作, 快去找
怎么了? 游侠竟然毫无防备?
佛罗多
我是亚玟, 我来帮助你
听到我的声音就回到光亮
她是谁?
佛罗多
－她是一个精灵 －他快死了
他撑不久的
一定要带他去找我父亲
－我找了你两天 －你要带他去哪儿?
有五名戒灵在跟着你 我不知道另外四个在哪里
陪着哈比人－ 我会来接你们
路上太危险了
他们在说什么?
如果我能渡河…
我不怕他们
亚玟…
拼命骑, 别回头
你在干嘛?! 戒灵在追杀他
把半身人交给我, 女精灵
如果你要他, 尽管来呀
不…
佛罗多, 别死
佛罗多, 别放弃
现在不行
请赐给我力量…
让他度过灾厄
让他免于死亡
救他
－我在哪里? －你在爱隆王的皇宫
现在是 10 月 24 日 早上 10 点
－甘道夫 －是, 我在这儿
你没有死算你幸运
再过几小时你就没救了
但是你的生命力真强
发生什么事?
－你怎么没去找我们? －对不起, 佛罗多
我有事耽搁了
你不能随便和我绝交
别再抗拒了, 没有用的
你不投靠魔戒…
就等着灭亡吧
世上只有一个魔戒之王
只有他能够驾驭魔戒
他不会和你分享权力
所以你选择了 死亡
甘道夫, 怎么了?
没事
佛罗多
－山姆 －你终于醒了
山姆一直守在你身边
我们好担心你, 对吧? 甘道夫
幸好有爱隆王, 你开始痊愈了
欢迎光临瑞文戴尔, 佛罗多巴金斯
－比尔博 －佛罗多, 好孩子
比尔博
" 去而复返:
哈比人的故事 " 比尔博巴金斯著
－太棒了 －我想再回去
我很想再去幽暗密林一趟
探访长湖镇
再看一眼孤山
但是我终于年老力衰了
夏尔
我好想家
我从小就幻想我能到别的地方
跟你一起去冒险
但是我自己的冒险 却完全不是这么回事
我跟你不一样, 比尔博
乖孩子
－我还忘了什么? －这么快就打包了?
越早准备越好
－你不是很想看精灵吗? －是啊
－你想看得不得了 －是啊
只是…
我们照甘道夫说的做了 不是吗?
我们把魔戒带到瑞文戴尔 我觉得…
你的伤快好了, 我们也该走了
回家
你说的对, 山姆
我们达成了任务
魔戒在这儿很安全
我可以回家了
他的体力恢复了
但他的伤永远无法痊愈 一辈子都会跟着他
经过这一路的冒险…
证明哈比人能抗拒魔戒的诱惑
他不该扛下这副重担
－佛罗多已经尽力了 －甘道夫,敌人正在蠢蠢欲动
索伦的大军在东方集结 他的邪眼正在盯着瑞文戴尔
你说萨鲁曼也背叛了我们
我们的盟友越来越少
他的恶行不只如此
他把半兽人和妖精混在一起
在艾辛格的洞窟培育一支军队
一支能在白天出没的劲旅
萨鲁曼要来抢夺至尊魔戒
精灵无法抵抗这股邪恶力量
我们对抗不了魔多和艾辛格!
甘道夫
至尊魔戒不能留在这儿
整个中土世界都受到威胁
他们必须决定如何拯救世界
精灵要卸下重担, 迁移到别处
我们走了你们要向谁求救? 矮人族吗?
他们都躲在山洞挖宝藏 一点都不关心别人的问题
我们要把希望放在人类身上
人类?
人类太脆弱了 他们没有希望了
登丹人的血液不再纯正 他们的骄傲和荣耀早被遗忘
魔戒会被留下来都是人类的错
当时我也在场
三千年前…
埃西铎取走至尊魔戒
人类受到诱惑那天我也在场
埃西铎, 跟我来
我带埃西铎来到末日火山
只有在那里才能摧毁至尊魔戒
把它丢进烈焰中
－毁了它 －不
埃西铎
那天就该结束一切 但是邪恶却存活下去
埃西铎把至尊魔戒占为己有
皇室血脉就此断绝 人类早已失去力量
－他们群龙无首四处流窜 －还有一个人能让他们团结
有一个人能继承刚铎王位
但他早就放弃王位了
他选择自我放逐
你不是精灵
我是南方来的人类
－你是谁? －我是灰袍巫师甘道夫的朋友
那我们来的目的一样…
朋友
纳希尔圣剑的碎片
这把利刃砍断索伦的手指
它还是很锐利
但现在它只是残缺的宝物
你为什么害怕过去?
虽然你是埃西铎的后代 但你并不是他
你不会重蹈他的覆辙
我身上流着跟他一样的血
一样的软弱
你的荣耀即将来临
你会面对同样的邪恶 然后击败它
邪恶的力量并没有征服我们
至少你我还没被征服
你记得我们第一次见面吗?
我好像走进了一个梦境
过了这么多年
你不再像当初一样年少轻狂
你还记得当初我说什么吗?
你说你愿意嫁给我
放弃精灵长生不死的力量
我仍愿意这么做
我宁愿和你共度一生
也不愿意面对永生不死的孤寂
我选择成为凡人
－你不能给我这个 －这是我的选择
像是我的心
来自远方的陌生人和老朋友
你们要商量如何对抗魔多
中土世界正面临灭亡的命运 无人能幸免
你们不团结一心就会遭到毁灭
每一个种族都无法幸免
把魔戒拿上来, 佛罗多
这果然是真的
我曾经在梦中
看到东方的天空暗淡
但是西方却只有一线微光
有一个声音在呐喊:
" 你即将面临灭亡的命运
埃西铎克星已被寻获 "
埃西铎克星
波罗莫
没有人敢在瑞文戴尔 说出魔多的邪恶语言
我并不想请求你的原谅 爱隆王
因为魔多的邪恶魔音
也许很快就会
响彻整个西方世界
魔戒是一种邪恶力量
它是一个礼物
一个对抗魔多的利器
何不利用这只魔戒?
我父亲是刚铎的宰相
他一直奋力和魔多抗争 我们流着鲜血…
保护你们的安全
把敌人的武器交给刚铎 让我们利用它来对抗邪恶
你无法驾驭它, 谁都不能
至尊魔戒的主人是索伦 它没有第二个主人
区区一个游侠懂什么?
他不只是游侠
他是亚拉冈, 亚拉松之子
你要对他效忠
亚拉冈
你是埃西铎的后代
也是刚铎的王位继承人
坐下来, 勒苟拉斯
刚铎没有国王
刚铎也不需要国王
亚拉冈说得对, 不能利用魔戒
你们只有一个选择
一定要摧毁至尊魔戒
那还等什么?
金雳, 葛罗音之子 在场的任何武器…
都无法摧毁至尊魔戒
魔戒是末日火山的烈焰铸成
也只有在那儿才能摧毁它
一定要深入魔多
把魔戒丢到末日火山的烈焰中
你们其中一个
必须去做
我们不能就这样闯进魔多
除了有半兽人看守黑色大门
还有永不松懈的邪恶力量
索伦的邪眼更是虎视耽耽
那是一片死寂的荒原
布满烈焰、灰烬和尘埃
光是空中就充满致命毒气
就算有千军万马也办不到 这是不可能的
你没听到爱隆王说的话吗? 一定要摧毁魔戒
难道你要自告奋勇吗?
失败了怎么办? 魔戒被索伦抢回去怎么办?
我绝不容许魔戒落入精灵手中
精灵都不可靠
大家在这儿争吵不休 索伦的力量就会越来越强
每个人都会遭到毁灭
我愿意
我愿意去
我愿意把魔戒带到魔多
虽然…
我不认得路
我愿意协助你, 佛罗多巴金斯
只要你愿背负重担
我愿意牺牲性命保护你的安危
我愿意
我的剑会保护你
还有我的弓箭
以及我的斧头
你背负着大家的命运
如果这是大家的决定
刚铎也会支持他
－佛罗多先生到哪儿我都要跟去 －没错, 是很难拆散你们
连你没份参加的秘密会议 你也跟来了
我们也要跟去
除非你把我们五花大绑送回家
你需要聪明人来完成这…
任务
或是冒险
这玩意
你第一个就不合格
九名同伴
就这样吧
你们就是魔戒远征队
帅呆了
我们要去哪儿呀?
她希望保护她的孩子
她以为你在瑞文戴尔会很安全
你母亲知道 你这辈子都会遭到追杀
你也逃避不了这个命运
精灵可以重新铸造王者之剑
但是只有你 拥有使用它的力量
我并不想拥有这力量
我从来都不想
你是唯一的人皇继承人 没有别人了
这是我的宝剑, 刺针
来, 拿去
－好轻哦 －没错, 这是精灵宝剑
半兽人接近剑身就会发亮
这样一来你就知道要格外小心
这玩意更棒
秘银
轻若鸿毛、韧如龙鳞
让我看你把它穿上, 快点
我的戒指
我真的很想…
再把它握在手中
我很抱歉把你卷进这件事
我很抱歉让你扛这重担
我对这一切都很抱歉
魔戒持有者要前往末日火山
你们这些同行的伙伴 并没有许下誓言…
或是受到约束 规定你们一定要走完全程
再会了, 别忘记你们的任务
愿精灵、人类 以及所有的自由之士
都能祝福你们
魔戒远征队等候魔戒持有者
甘道夫 魔多是往左还是往右?
往左
我们必须向 迷雾山脉以西走四十天
幸运的话就能赶到洛汗隘口
从那儿往东走到魔多
二、一、五, 好! 非常好
脚步要快
－你好帅哦, 皮聘 －谢了
快一点
虽然你们都不问我的意见
我还是要说我们在绕远路
我们大可以穿过摩瑞亚矿坑
我表哥巴林会热烈欢迎我们
不行 别无选择才能走摩瑞亚矿坑
对不起
抓住他
－夏尔万岁 －把他压住
别闹了
你抓住我了
－那是什么? －只是一朵乌云
它迎着风
移动得很快
－登兰德的乌鸦 －快躲起来
－快点 －躲起来
萨鲁曼的眼线
南方的路受到监视
我们一定要攀越卡兰拉斯山
佛罗多
波罗莫
我们受尽了恐惧和疑虑的折磨
就为了这小玩意
这小小的玩意
波罗莫
把魔戒还给佛罗多
遵命
我才不要它
甘道夫, 你想带他们 攀越卡兰拉斯山
要是失败, 你能到哪儿?
要是你被高山峻岭打败
你肯冒更大的危险吗?
空中有可怕的声音
那是萨鲁曼
他想造成山崩 我们一定要回头, 甘道夫
不行
我们一定要离开山岭
赶到洛汗隘口 从西谷到我的城市
洛汗隘口离艾辛格太近了
上面走不成就走下面吧
让我们穿过摩瑞亚矿坑
摩瑞亚? 你很怕穿过矿坑
矮人太贪心, 挖得太深
你知道他们在 凯撒督姆的黑暗中唤醒什么
邪恶的炎魔
让魔戒持有者决定
我们不能待在这儿
我们留下来就死定了
佛罗多?
我们穿过矿坑吧
就这么办吧
佛罗多, 过来扶扶我这老头儿
你的肩伤还好吧?
－好多了 －魔戒呢?
你感觉到它的力量 越来越大, 对吧?
我也感觉到了, 你要千万小心
邪恶力量不但会来自外面
恐怕也会来自远征队员
－我该相信谁? －你要相信自己
相信自己的力量
－什么意思? －这世上有很多力量
正义或邪恶的力量
有些力量比我更大
有些敌人连我都没有遭遇过
摩瑞亚矿坑的…
墙
矮人打造的门 关起来是看不到的
没错, 如果秘密被遗忘 连它们的主人都找不到
我怎么一点都不吃惊?
让我看看
伊希尔丁金属
它只会反射星光和月光
上面写着: "都灵之门、摩瑞亚之主"
－开口说, 朋友, 然后进入 －那是什么意思?
很简单 如果是朋友, 说出暗语门就开了
没有反应
我以前知道所有精灵和人类
甚至是半兽人的咒语
你打算怎么办?
用你的头把大门撞开
要是这样还撞不开
你就别再烦我 让我静下来好好想一想
该用什么咒语才能开门
马儿不能进入矿坑
－就算它很勇敢也不行 －再见了, 比尔
去吧, 比尔
放心, 它认得回家的路
别玩水
没有用
这是一个谜语
开口说 "朋友", 然后进入
"朋友" 的精灵话怎么说?
(精灵语)
你很快就会见到矮人族的热情
熊熊的火焰、清凉的啤酒 大块的烤肉
这就是我表哥巴林的家
这怎么会只是矿坑呢?
当然不是
这不是矿坑, 这是坟墓
不…
不!
半兽人
我们应该去洛汗隘口 不应该来这儿
快走, 快呀
－佛罗多 －救命呀
神行客
－救我 －放开他
亚拉冈
佛罗多
快进去矿坑
－勒苟拉斯 －快进去
快跑
现在只有一个选择
我们一定要穿过黑暗的矿坑
大家要提高警觉
有比半兽人更可怕的怪物
在这个黑暗的地底世界
安静, 要走四天才能到另一边
希望我们不会惊动什么
摩瑞亚矿坑最珍贵的不是黄金
或是珠宝
而是秘银
索林给了比尔博一件 秘银打造的锁甲
－简直是给国王的礼物 －没错
我从来没跟他说过
但那件秘银价值连城 可以买下整个夏尔
皮聘
我不记得这地方
－我们迷路了吗? －没有
－应该迷路了 －甘道夫正在想
－梅里? －干嘛?
我饿了
－下面有东西 －那是咕鲁
－咕鲁? －他跟了我们三天
－他从巴拉多的地牢逃出来? －逃出来…
或是被放出来吧
他是为了魔戒而来
他对魔戒永远充满渴望
他对至尊魔戒又爱又恨 就像他对自己爱恨交加
史麦戈的遭遇很悲惨
史麦戈是咕鲁的本名 在他找到魔戒之前
在魔戒让他发疯之前
可惜比尔博没杀了他
可惜?
比尔博是可怜他才没杀他
有很多活人本来就该死 也有些死人本来命不该
你能做这种判断吗? 佛罗多?
千万别轻易断定别人的生死
就连智者都无法决定命运
我直觉地认为不管是好是坏 咕鲁都会跟这趟冒险有关…
在一切结束前
比尔博一时心软影响了很多人
我真希望魔戒没在我手中
真希望这一切都没发生
每个人遇到难关都会这么想 但是我们无法决定自己的命运
我们要决定的是 在一定的时间内怎么去做
世上除了邪恶还有别的力量
比尔博注定要找到魔戒
你也注定要得到它
能这么想就好了
这个方向
－他记起来了 －不是
但是这儿的空气没那么糟
要是迷了路跟着鼻子走就对了
让我再弄亮一点
看吧
这就是宏伟的矮人故乡摩瑞亚
这真是令人大开眼界
金雳
不!
不
"巴林长眠于此
方丁之子
摩瑞亚之王"
他死了
果然跟我担心的一样
快走吧, 别在这儿逗留
他们攻下桥梁和第二大厅
我们闩住大门
却阻挡不了他们
大地在撼动
鼓声
地底深处传来鼓声
我们逃不出去
黑暗中有一个阴影
他们来了"
你这个蠢小子
下次你自己也跳下去算了
佛罗多先生
半兽人
退后, 跟着甘道夫
有一只食人妖
让它们来吧
摩瑞亚有一个矮人还没死哩
我越来越厉害了
佛罗多
亚拉冈
不要
他还活着
我没事, 我没受伤
你应该没命的
那一剑连野猪都能刺死
小哈比人远比我们想像的厉害
秘银
你真是叫人吃惊, 巴金斯
快到凯萨督姆桥
这边
又来了什么怪物?
炎魔
远古的恶魔
你们都不是它的对手
快跑
快点
甘道夫
你带领他们, 亚拉冈
桥就快到了
听我的话 剑是无法对付炎魔的
甘道夫
梅里! 皮聘!
山姆!
谁也不能丢矮人
别扯我胡子
稳着点
站好
稳住
往前倾
快点
快跳
快过桥
快过去
你不能过来
甘道夫
我是圣火的仆人 高举着亚尔诺炽焰
邪恶之火不会帮你 乌顿之火!
滚回黑暗中吧
你不能过来!
－不! 不! －甘道夫!
快走啊，你这傻瓜
不!
亚拉冈
勒苟拉斯, 把他们扶起来
让他们静一静吧
天一黑半兽人就会蜂拥而上
我们一定要赶到罗斯洛立安
走吧, 波罗莫、勒苟拉斯 金雳, 把他们扶起来
起来, 山姆
佛罗多先生?
佛罗多
跟紧了
听说这儿住了可怕的女巫师
她是一个精灵
拥有强大法力
只要看她一眼
就会被她蛊惑
佛罗多
然后永远消失
你来到这里 带来毁灭的消息
你把邪恶带来, 魔戒持有者
佛罗多先生?
她可骗不了我这矮人
我有老鹰的锐眼、狐狸的耳朵
这矮子太聒噪 就算闭着眼睛也能毙了他
欢迎, 勒苟拉斯, 瑟兰督伊之子
魔戒远征队需要你帮忙
登丹人亚拉冈
我们久仰你的大名
你们精灵 不是一向都很有礼貌吗?
说我们也听得懂的话
自从黑暗时期 我们就没跟矮人打过交道
你知道我这矮人会怎么说吗?
你这样很没有礼貌
你们带来强大的邪恶力量
你们不能再前进
你不能让甘道夫白白牺牲
他也不会要你放弃希望
你身负重任, 佛罗多
千万别被死亡的阴影打败
跟我来
卡拉斯加拉顿
黄金森林中的精灵城市
凯勒布理安公主 以及光明女王凯兰崔尔的国度
敌人知道你们来到这里
你们已经曝露了行踪
这儿只有八人 但有九人从瑞文戴尔出发
甘道夫呢?
我想跟他说话
我在这儿看不到他
灰袍巫师甘道夫 并没有进入黄金森林
他已坠入黑暗深渊
他被烈焰和黑暗吞噬
魔苟斯的炎魔
我们不小心进入 摩瑞亚矿坑的陷阱
甘道夫做事一向都很小心
我们还不知道他的意图
别让凯萨督姆的毁灭 让你灰心丧志
金雳, 葛罗音之子
世上充满危险
到处都是困难重重
你们的心中充满悲伤
现在魔戒远征队会怎么样?
甘道夫死后就没有希望了
这趟旅程险象环生
你们只要一不小心就会失败
世界末日也会降临
只要你们团结一致就有希望
你们的信心不能动摇 快去休息吧
你们有太多的哀伤和疲惫
今晚你们要好好睡一觉…
欢迎, 夏尔的佛罗多
只有你见过邪眼
他们在为甘道夫哀悼
他们说些什么?
我不忍心告诉你们
我的伤痛尚未平息
他们一定没提到他放的烟火
他们应该作诗来歌颂这一点
从古到今最棒的烟火
在空中闪烁就像耀眼的星斗
这些闪闪发光的烟火 就像银河一样从天而降
就跟天空飘下的花雨一样缤纷
这都不足以形容它们有多壮观
快休息吧
这里很安全
我在这里无法休息
我听到她的声音
她提到我父亲和刚铎的灭亡
她说现在仍有一线希望
但是我却看不到
我们长久以来都没有希望
我父亲拥有高贵情操
但是他无法统治刚铎
人民也失去信心
他希望我能成功, 我也希望
我想要重建刚铎的荣耀
你见过吗?
爱克西里昂的白塔
就像珍珠一般闪闪发亮
塔上的旗子随风飘扬
你有没有听过
银号角的召唤声?
我很久以前见过…
这白色城市
有一天, 我们将一起去那儿
到时候守卫将高喊
"刚铎之主回来了"
请你看着镜子
我会看到什么?
最聪明的智者也不知道
因为镜子
能显现各种事情
过去的事情
现在的事情
还有一些
尚未发生的事情
我知道你看到什么
它一样也在我心里呈现
如果你失败就会发生这些事
魔戒远征队已经开始四分五裂
他会试图抢走魔戒
你知道我说的是谁
他们会一个接一个被魔戒击垮
只要你开口
我就把至尊魔戒给你
你肯毫无条件地给我?
我承认我很想要魔戒
我将成为魔戒之后
她并不黑暗, 而是美丽 跟曙光一样耀眼
跟海洋一样高深莫测
远比土地更加坚强
世人都将迷恋我
而且自暴自弃 而且自暴自弃
我通过了试炼
我将退隐到西方
－继续当凯兰崔尔女王 －我一个人无法摧毁它
你是魔戒持有者, 佛罗多 持有至尊魔戒
就必须孤单一个人
这是南雅, 钻石魔戒
我是它的持有者
这是你的使命
如果你办不到
也没有人可以
我知道该怎么做了
只是…
我感到害怕
再渺小的人也能改变未来
你知道半兽人是怎么来的吗?
它们曾经是精灵
但是却被黑暗力量
折磨到不成人形
它们是被扭曲的可怕生物
却在我手中
达到完美境界
我的强兽人战士
你的主人是谁?
萨鲁曼
猎杀他们 找不到他们绝不罢手
你们没有痛苦也没有恐惧
你们只会杀人
有一个半身人手中有宝物
我要你毫发无伤地活抓他
杀了其他的人
我们从来没有让外人 穿上我们精灵的衣服
希望这些精灵斗篷 能让你们躲过敌人的侦察
这是兰巴斯
精灵的干粮
只要咬一小口 就能让一个成年人填饱肚子
你吃了几块?
四块
你们每向南方走一步 就离危险更接近一步
魔多的半兽人 占领了安都因河东岸
但是西岸也并不安全
萨鲁曼的白掌部队 曾经出没在我们的边界
半兽人不能在大太阳下行动 但是这些怪物却可以
他们在追杀你们
只有走水路才有可能 赶在敌人前面到达拉洛斯瀑布
勒苟拉斯, 我送你的礼物 是凯兰崔姆弓箭
能让你拥有百步穿杨的绝技
这些是诺多伦短剑
曾经在战场上杀敌无数
千万别害怕, 小彼利坚.图克
你会找到你的勇气
还有你, 山姆卫斯詹吉
我送你十一条 希斯蓝制作的绳子
谢谢你, 女王
这些漂亮的短剑都用完了吗?
矮人要向精灵要什么礼物?
什么都不要
我只想再看凯兰崔姆女王 最后一眼就已足够了
因为她比地底蕴藏的 所有的珠宝都更加美丽
不过呢
我是有一个要求
不过我不敢奢想 这是不可能实现的愿望
我也不该开口
我不能再给你什么
因为你已拥有最珍贵的礼物
那就是亚玟的爱
但是我怕亚玟会越来越虚弱
所以我要让她离开中土世界
跟其他的精灵在一起
我会要她坐船到瓦林诺
她必须面对这个抉择
你也必须做出决定, 亚拉冈
重建自伊兰迪尔以后 你的先祖创造的辉煌成就
或是带着你仅存的子民 坠入绝望的黑暗深渊
再会了
你尚未完全发挥你的潜力
但是我们将不会再见面
伊力萨
再见了, 佛罗多巴金斯
我将埃兰迪尔之光送给你
这是我们最挚爱的星辰
愿它在所有光亮熄灭时
在黑暗中为你照亮光明
这种离别是最感伤的
因为这是我最后一次 看到世上最美丽的女王
从此以后除非是她的礼物 在我眼中没有什么是美丽的
她送你什么礼物?
我向她要一根她头上的头发
她给了我三根
那是咕鲁 他从摩瑞亚矿坑一直在跟踪我们
我以为在河上就能甩掉他
可惜他的水性很好
如果他把我们的行踪告诉敌人
我们想要渡河就会更危险
吃点东西吧, 佛罗多先生
－不要 －你一整天都没吃过东西
你也睡得很不安稳 别以为我没注意到
－佛罗多先生 －我很好
你并不好
我是来帮你的
我答应甘道夫我会守在你身边
你帮不了我, 山姆
这次不行
去睡吧
到米那斯提力斯比较安全
我们可以在那里养精蓄锐
然后一鼓作气攻向魔多
刚铎也帮不了我们
你倒是很愿意接受精灵的帮忙
你对你自己的人民 一点信心都没有吗?
他们的力量是很薄弱 意志也不够坚定
但是人类拥有无比的勇气 和高贵的情操
可是你都看不到
你很害怕
你这辈子都躲在阴影下
不敢承认你自己的身份
我不会把魔戒带到你的城市
佛罗多
亚苟那斯巨像
我一直都想仰望过往的国王
我的祖先
天一黑我们就渡湖
把船藏好再用走的
－从北边进入魔多 －是吗?
只要通过爱明莫尔就行了
那是充满尖石的迷宫
然后呢, 更精采了
那儿有一望无际的臭沼泽地
我们要走这条路
休息吧, 你要养精蓄锐
养精蓄锐个头
－最好马上启程 －不行
半兽人在巡逻东岸 我们一定要等到天黑再出发
我担心的不是东岸
我心中一直 有一个阴影和威胁
有什么正在接近, 我感觉得到
矮人族才不必养精蓄锐 别理他, 小哈比人
佛罗多呢?
我们都不该一个人乱跑
尤其是你
你的责任重大
佛罗多?
我知道你想一个人静静
我每天都看着你受苦
你确定你不是白白受苦吗?
有其它的路, 佛罗多
－我们可以走另一条路 －我知道你想说什么
好像很有道理, 但我得到警告
警告? 什么警告?
我们都很害怕
但如果让恐惧摧毁一切希望
－未免太不值得了吧? －没有别的路可走
我只想得到捍卫人民的力量
－只要你把魔戒借我 －不行
－别害怕, 我不是强盗 －你失去了理智
你以为你能成功吗?
他们会找到你, 把魔戒抢走
让你求生不能、求死不得
你这傻瓜
你只是靠运气得到它 它应该是我的
它应该是我的, 给我吧
－快给我 －不
－给我 －不
我知道了
你会把魔戒交给索伦
你会背叛我们
你会害我们跟你一起死
我诅咒你和所有的半身人
佛罗多?
佛罗多
我做了什么?
求求你, 佛罗多
佛罗多, 对不起
佛罗多?
－它蛊惑了波罗莫 －魔戒呢?
别过来
佛罗多
－我发誓要保护你 －你能保证不害我吗?
你会摧毁它吗?
亚拉冈
伊力萨
我愿意跟随你到最后
跟随你到魔多烈焰
我明白了
好好照顾他们 尤其是山姆, 他不会了解
去吧, 佛罗多
快跑啊
快跑
佛罗多先生
去找半身人
快去找半身人
伊兰迪尔!
亚拉冈, 快走
佛罗多
快躲过来
快呀
他在干嘛?
他要离开了
－不! －皮聘!
快跑吧, 佛罗多
－喂 －你！我在这儿
－这里啊 －这边
－成功了 －我知道啦, 快跑
－刚铎号角 －波罗莫
快跑
不
－他们把小个子抓走了 －别动
佛罗多在哪里?
我让他走了
你做到我做不到的事
我试着抢走魔戒
－现在谁也抢不走魔戒了 －原谅我
我没有想到
－我让大家失望了 －不, 波罗莫
你很英勇
你维持了你的尊严
算了
一切都结束了
人类世界将灭亡 黑暗将笼罩大地
我们的城市将遭毁灭
我不知道我有多少力量
但我发誓绝不会让白城沦陷
也不会让我们的人民失败
我们的人民
我愿跟随你, 我的兄弟
我的领袖
我的国王
安息吧
刚铎之子
他们会在白塔等待他的归来
但是他永远不会回去了
佛罗多
我真希望魔戒没在我手中
真希望这一切都没发生
每个人遇到难关都会这么想
但是我们无法决定自己的命运
你只能想…
该如何完成你被赋与的使命
不、不、不
佛罗多
－佛罗多先生 －不, 山姆
回去吧, 山姆
－我要一个人去魔多 －没问题
但我要跟你一起去
你不会游泳
山姆
山姆!
我许下一个承诺, 佛罗多先生
这个承诺是 : "千万别离开他, 山姆卫斯詹吉"
我绝不会离开你
绝对不会
山姆
来吧
快, 他们就快到东岸了
－你不打算跟去? －我们帮不了佛罗多了
我们一切的努力都白费了 远征队也彻底失败
我们的努力不会白费
我们不能丢下梅里和皮聘 让他们受苦
只要我们还有力气 把用不着的东西留下来
尽量减轻负担
让我们猎杀半兽人吧
好耶
魔多
希望其他人走的路比较安全
神行客会照顾他们的
我们大概不会再见到他们了
也许还会再见
也许会
山姆
我很高兴有你陪着我
The world is changed.
I feel it in the water.
I feel it in the earth.
I smell it in the air.
Much that once was...
...is lost.
For none now live who remember it.
It began with the forging of the Great Rings.
Three were given to the Elves:
Immortal, wisest and fairest of all beings.
Seven to the Dwarf-lords:
Great miners and craftsmen of the mountain halls.
And nine...
...nine rings were gifted to the race of Men...
...who, above all else, desire power.
For within these rings was bound the strength and will to govern each race.
But they were all of them deceived.
For another ring was made.
In the land of Mordor, in the fires of Mount Doom...
...the Dark Lord Sauron forged in secret a Master Ring...
...to control all others.
And into this Ring he poured his cruelty, his malice...
...and his will to dominate all life.
One Ring to rule them all.
One by one...
...the Free Lands of Middle-earth fell to the power of the Ring.
But there were some who resisted.
A Last Alliance of Men and Elves marched against the armies of Mordor.
And on the slopes of Mount Doom, they fought for the freedom of Middle-earth.
Victory was near.
But the power of the Ring...
...could not be undone.
It was in this moment...
...when all hope had faded...
...that Isildur, son of the king, took up his father's sword.
Sauron, the enemy of the Free Peoples of Middle-earth, was defeated.
The Ring passed to Isildur...
...who had this one chance to destroy evil forever.
But the hearts of Men...
...are easily corrupted.
And the Ring of Power has a will of its own.
It betrayed Isildur...
...to his death.
And some things that should not have been forgotten...
...were lost.
History became legend...
...legend became myth.
And for two and a half thousand years...
...the Ring passed out of all knowledge.
Until, when chance came...
...it ensnared a new bearer.
My precious.
The Ring came to the creature Gollum...
...who took it deep into the tunnels of the Misty Mountains.
And there it consumed him.
It came to me.
My own. My love. My own.
My precious.
The Ring brought to Gollum unnatural long life.
For 500 years it poisoned his mind.
And in the gloom of Gollum 's cave, it waited.
Darkness crept back into the forests of the world.
Rumor grew of a shadow in the East...
...whispers of a nameless fear.
And the Ring of Power perceived...
...its time had now come.
It abandoned Gollum.
But something happened then the Ring did not intend.
It was picked up by the most unlikely creature imaginable.
What's this?
A Hobbit.
Bilbo Baggins of the Shire.
A ring.
Lost!
My precious is lost!
For the time will soon come...
...when Hobbits will shape the fortunes of all.
The 22nd day of September...
...in the year 1400...
...by Shire-reckoning.
Bag End, Bagshot Row, Hobbiton, Westfarthing...
...the Shire...
...Middle-earth.
The Third Age of this world.
There and Back Again:
A Hobbit's Tale.
By Bilbo Baggins.
Now...
...where to begin?
Ah, yes....
"Concerning...
...Hobbits."
Hobbits have been living and farming in the four Farthings of the Shire...
...for many hundreds of years...
...quite content to ignore and be ignored...
...by the world of the Big Folk.
Middle-earth being, after all, full of strange creatures beyond count...
...Hobbits must seem of little importance...
...being neither renowned as great warriors...
...nor counted among the very wise.
Frodo! Someone at the door.
In fact, it has been remarked by some...
...that Hobbits' only real passion is for food.
A rather unfair observation...
...as we have also developed a keen interest in the brewing of ales...
...and the smoking of pipe-weed.
But where our hearts truly lie...
...is in peace and quiet...
...and good, tilled earth.
For all Hobbits share a love of things that grow.
And, yes, no doubt to others, our ways seem quaint.
But today of all days, it is brought home to me:
It is no bad thing to celebrate a simple life.
Frodo, the door!
Sticklebacks. Where is that boy?
Frodo!
Down from the door where it began
And I must follow if I can
The road goes ever on and on
Down from the door where it began
Now far ahead the road has gone
- And I must follow if I can - You're late.
A wizard is never late, Frodo Baggins.
Nor is he early. He arrives precisely when he means to.
It's wonderful to see you, Gandalf!
You didn't think I'd miss your Uncle Bilbo's birthday?
How is the old rascal?
I hear it's going to be a party of special magnificence.
You know Bilbo. He's got the whole place in an uproar.
Well, that should please him.
Half the Shire's been invited.
And the rest of them are turning up anyway.
And so life in the Shire goes on...
...very much as it has this past Age...
...full of its own comings and goings, with change coming slowly.
If it comes at all.
For things are made to endure in the Shire...
...passing from one generation to the next.
There 's always been a Baggins living here under the Hill...
...in Bag End.
And there always will be.
To tell you the truth, Bilbo's been a bit odd lately.
I mean, more than usual.
He's taken to locking himself in his study.
He spends hours poring over old maps when he thinks I'm not looking.
Where's it gone?
He's up to something.
- All right, then. Keep your secrets. - What?
But I know you have something to do with it.
Good gracious me.
Before you came along, we Bagginses were very well thought of.
Indeed.
Never had any adventures or did anything unexpected.
If you're referring to the incident with the dragon, I was barely involved.
All I did was give your uncle a little nudge out of the door.
Whatever you did, you've been officially labeled a disturber of the peace.
Oh, really?
Gandalf! Gandalf!
Fireworks, Gandalf!
- Gandalf! - Fireworks, Gandalf!
Gandalf?
- I'm glad you're back. - So am I, dear boy.
So am I.
No, thank you!
We don't want any more visitors, well-wishers or distant relations!
And what about very old friends?
Gandalf?
- Bilbo Baggins. - My dear Gandalf!
Good to see you. 111 years old! Who would believe it?
You haven't aged a day.
Come on, come in!
Welcome, welcome.
Oh, here we are.
Tea? Or maybe something a little stronger?
I've got a few bottles of the Old Winyard left. 1296.
Very good year. Almost as old as I am.
It was laid down by my father. What say we open one, eh?
Just tea, thank you.
I was expecting you sometime last week.
Not that it matters. You come and go as you please. Always have and always will.
You caught me a bit unprepared. We've only got cold chicken and a bit of pickle....
There's some cheese here. No, that won't do.
We've got raspberry jam, an apple tart....
But not much for afters. Oh, no, we're all right.
I've just found some sponge cake.
I could make you some eggs if you'd--
- Just tea, thank you. - Oh, right.
- You don't mind if I eat, do you? - No, not at all.
Bilbo! Bilbo Baggins!
I'm not at home!
It's the Sackville-Bagginses.
- I know you're in there! - They're after the house.
They've never forgiven me for living this long.
I've got to get away from these confounded relatives, hanging on the bell all day...
...never giving me a moment's peace.
I want to see mountains again. Mountains, Gandalf!
And then find somewhere quiet where I can finish my book. Oh, tea.
- So you mean to go through with your plan? - Yes, yes. It's all in hand.
All the arrangements are made.
Oh, thank you.
Frodo suspects something.
Of course he does. He's a Baggins...
...not some blockheaded Bracegirdle from Hardbottle.
You will tell him, won't you?
- Yes, yes. - He's very fond of you.
I know.
He'd probably come with me if I asked him.
I think in his heart, Frodo's still in love with the Shire.
The woods, the fields.
Little rivers.
I am old, Gandalf.
I know I don't look it, but I'm beginning to feel it in my heart.
I feel thin.
Sort of stretched...
...like butter scraped over too much bread.
I need a holiday. A very long holiday.
And I don't expect I shall return.
In fact, I mean not to.
Old Toby. The finest weed in the Southfarthing.
Gandalf, my old friend...
...this will be a night to remember.
Hello, hello.
Fatty Bolger. Lovely to see you. Welcome, welcome.
Go on, Sam. Ask Rosie for a dance.
- I think I'll just have another ale. - Oh, no, you don't.
Go on!
So there I was...
...at the mercy of three monstrous trolls.
And they were all arguing amongst themselves...
...about how they were going to cook us.
Whether it be turned on a spit, or to sit on us one by one, squash us into jelly.
They spent so much time arguing the whithertos and the whyfors...
...that the sun's first light crept over the top of the trees...
...and turned them all to stone!
Quickly.
Up they go!
No, the big one.
Mrs. Bracegirdle, how nice to see you. Welcome, welcome.
Are all these children yours?
Good gracious, you have been productive.
Bilbo?
Sackville-Bagginses!
Quickly, hide!
Thank you, my boy.
You're a good lad, Frodo.
I'm very selfish, you know.
Yes, I am. Very selfish.
I don't know why I took you in after your mother and father died...
...but it wasn't out of charity.
I think it was because...
...of all my numerous relations...
...you were the one Baggins that showed real spirit.
Bilbo, have you been at the Gaffer's home brew?
No.
Well, yes, but that's not the point.
The point is, Frodo...
...you'll be all right.
- Done! - You're supposed to stick it in the ground.
- It is in the ground. - Outside!
This was your idea.
Bilbo.
Bilbo, watch out for the dragon!
Nonsense. There hasn't been a dragon in these parts for a thousand years.
- That was good. - Let's get another one.
Meriadoc Brandybuck and Peregrin Took.
I might've known.
Speech, Bilbo!
Speech!
My dear Bagginses and Boffins...
...Tooks and Brandybucks...
...Grubbs, Chubbs...
...Hornblowers...
...Bolgers...
...Bracegirdles...
- ...and Proudfoots. - Proudfeet!
Today is my 111th birthday!
Happy birthday!
But alas, eleventy-one years is far too short a time to live among...
...such excellent and admirable Hobbits.
I don't know half of you half as well as I should like...
...and I like less than half of you half as well as you deserve.
I have things to do.
I've put this off far too long.
I regret to announce this is the end!
I'm going now.
I bid you all a very fond farewell.
Goodbye.
I suppose you think that was terribly clever.
Come on, Gandalf. Did you see their faces?
There are many magic rings in this world, and none of them should be used lightly.
It was just a bit of fun.
Oh, you're probably right, as usual.
- You will keep an eye on Frodo, won't you? - Two eyes.
As often as I can spare them.
- I'm leaving everything to him. - What about this ring of yours?
- Is that staying too? - Yes, yes.
It's in an envelope over there on the mantelpiece.
No. Wait, it's...
...here in my pocket.
Isn't that--? Isn't that odd, now?
Yet, after all, why not?
- Why shouldn't I keep it? - I think you should leave the ring behind.
Is that so hard?
Well, no.
And yes.
Now it comes to it, I don't feel like parting with it.
It's mine. I found it! It came to me!
- There's no need to get angry. - Well, if I'm angry, it's your fault!
It's mine.
My own.
- My precious. - Precious?
It's been called that before, but not by you.
What business is it of yours what I do with my own things?
I think you've had that ring quite long enough.
- You want it for yourself! - Bilbo Baggins!
Do not take me for some conjurer of cheap tricks.
I am not trying to rob you.
I'm trying to help you.
All your long years, we've been friends.
Trust me as you once did.
Let it go.
You're right, Gandalf.
The ring must go to Frodo.
It's late. The road is long.
Yes, it is time.
Bilbo, the ring is still in your pocket.
I've thought up an ending for my book:
"And he lived happily ever after to the end of his days."
And I'm sure you will, my dear friend.
Goodbye, Gandalf.
Goodbye, dear Bilbo.
The road goes ever on and on
Until our next meeting.
It's mine. My own.
My precious.
Riddles in the dark.
Bilbo!
My precious.
Precious.
He's gone, hasn't he?
He talked for so long about leaving...
...I didn't think he'd really do it.
Gandalf?
Bilbo's ring.
He's gone to stay with the Elves.
He's left you Bag End.
Along with all his possessions.
The ring is yours now.
- Put it somewhere out of sight. - Where are you going?
- There are some things that I must see to. - What things?
- Questions. Questions that need answering. - You've only just arrived.
I don't understand.
Neither do I.
Keep it secret.
Keep it safe.
Shire!
Baggins!
"The year 3434 of the Second Age.
Here follows the account of Isildur, High King of Gondor...
...and the finding of the Ring of Power. "
"It has come to me.
The One Ring. It shall be an heirloom of my kingdom.
All those who follow in my bloodline shall be bound to its fate...
...for I will risk no hurt to the Ring.
It is precious to me...
...though I buy it with great pain.
The markings upon the band begin to fade.
The writing, which at first was as clear as red flame, has all but disappeared.
A secret now that only fire can tell. "
Shire.
Baggins.
There's no Bagginses around here. They're all up in Hobbiton.
That way.
To heal my heart and drown my woe
Rain may fall and wind may blow
But there still be
Many miles to go
Sweet is the sound of the pouring rain
And the stream that falls From hill to plain
Better than rain or rippling brook
Is a mug of beer inside this Took
There's been some strange folk crossing the Shire.
Dwarves and others of a less than savory nature.
War is brewing.
The mountains are fair teeming with goblins.
Far-off tales and children's stories, that's all that is.
You're beginning to sound like that old Bilbo Baggins. Cracked, he was.
Young Mr. Frodo here, he's cracking.
And proud of it.
- Cheers, Gaffer. - Cheers.
It's none of our concern what goes on beyond our borders.
Keep your nose out of trouble, and no trouble'll come to you.
- Good night, lads. - Good night.
Good night, sweet maiden of the golden ale.
Mind who you're sweet-talking.
Don't worry, Sam. Rosie knows an idiot when she sees one.
Does she?
- Good night, Sam. - Good night, Mister Frodo.
Is it secret? Is it safe?
What are you doing?
Hold out your hand, Frodo.
It's quite cool.
What can you see?
Can you see anything?
Nothing.
There's nothing.
Wait.
There are markings.
It's some form of Elvish. I can't read it.
There are few who can.
The language is that of Mordor, which I will not utter here.
Mordor!
In the common tongue, it says:
"One Ring to rule them all...
...One Ring to find them...
...One Ring to bring them all...
...and in the darkness bind them."
This is the One Ring...
...forged by the Dark Lord Sauron in the fires of Mount Doom.
Taken by Isildur from the hand of Sauron himself.
Bilbo found it.
- In Gollum's cave. - Yes.
For 60 years, the Ring lay quiet in Bilbo's keeping...
...prolonging his life, delaying old age.
But no longer, Frodo. Evil is stirring in Mordor.
The Ring has awoken.
It's heard its master's call.
But he was destroyed. Sauron was destroyed.
No, Frodo.
The spirit of Sauron endured.
His life force is bound to the Ring, and the Ring survived.
Sauron has returned.
His Orcs have multiplied.
His fortress at Barad-dur is rebuilt in the land of Mordor.
Sauron needs only this Ring to cover all the lands in a second darkness.
He is seeking it.
Seeking it. All his thought is bent on it.
For the Ring yearns above all else...
...to return to the hand of its master.
They are one...
...the Ring and the Dark Lord.
Frodo...
...he must never find it.
All right.
We put it away. We keep it hidden. We never speak of it again.
No one knows it's here, do they?
Do they, Gandalf?
There is one other who knew that Bilbo had the Ring.
I looked everywhere for the creature Gollum.
But the enemy found him first.
I don't know how long they tortured him.
But amidst the endless screams and inane babble, they discerned two words:
Shire!
Baggins!
Shire.
Baggins. But that would lead them here!
Who goes there?
Take it, Gandalf!
- Take it! - No, Frodo.
- You must take it! - You cannot offer me this ring!
- I'm giving it to you! - Don't tempt me, Frodo!
I dare not take it.
Not even to keep it safe.
Understand, Frodo...
...I would use this Ring from a desire to do good.
But through me, it would wield a power too great and terrible to imagine.
- But it cannot stay in the Shire! - No.
No, it can't.
What must I do?
- You must leave. And leave quickly. - Where? Where do I go?
Get out of the Shire. Make for the village of Bree.
Bree.
- What about you? - I'll be waiting for you...
...at the inn of the Prancing Pony.
- And the Ring will be safe there? - I don't know, Frodo.
I don't have any answers.
I must see the head of my order. He is both wise and powerful. Trust me, Frodo.
He'll know what to do.
You'll have to leave the name of Baggins behind you.
That name is not safe outside the Shire.
Travel only by day. And stay off the road.
I can cut across country easily enough.
My dear Frodo.
Hobbits really are amazing creatures.
You can learn all that there is to know about their ways in a month.
And yet, after a hundred years...
...they can still surprise you.
Get down.
Confound it all, Samwise Gamgee! Have you been eavesdropping?
I haven't been dropping no eaves. Honest. I was cutting the grass under the window.
A little late for trimming the verge, don't you think?
- I heard raised voices. - What did you hear? Speak!
Nothing important.
That is, I heard a good deal about a ring, a Dark Lord and the end of the world but--
Please, Mr. Gandalf, sir, don't hurt me. Don't turn me into anything unnatural.
No?
Perhaps not.
I've thought of a better use for you.
Come along, Samwise. Keep up.
Be careful, both of you.
The enemy has many spies in his service:
Birds, beasts.
Is it safe?
Never put it on...
...for the agents of the Dark Lord will be drawn to its power.
Always remember, Frodo...
...the Ring is trying to get back to its master.
It wants to be found.
This is it.
This is what?
If I take one more step...
...it'll be the farthest away from home I've ever been.
Come on, Sam.
Remember what Bilbo used to say:
- "It's a dangerous business, Frodo." - "Going out your door.
You step onto the road, and if you don't keep your feet...
...there's no knowing where you might be swept off to. "
Sam.
Wood-elves.
They're going to the harbor beyond the White Towers.
To the Grey Havens.
They're leaving Middle-earth.
Never to return.
I don't know why...
...it makes me sad.
Everywhere I lie there's a dirty great root sticking into my back.
Just shut your eyes...
...and imagine you're back in your own bed...
...with a soft mattress and a lovely feather pillow.
It's not working, Mr. Frodo.
I'm never going to be able to sleep out here.
Me neither, Sam.
Smoke rises from the Mountain of Doom.
The hour grows late.
And Gandalf the Grey rides to Isengard...
...seeking my counsel.
For that is why you have come, is it not?
My old friend.
Saruman.
- You are sure of this? - Beyond any doubt.
So the Ring of Power has been found.
All these long years, it was in the Shire.
- Under my very nose. - Yet you did not have the wit to see it.
Your love of the halfling's leaf has clearly slowed your mind.
But we still have time. Time enough to counter Sauron if we act quickly.
Time?
What time do you think we have?
Sauron has regained much of his former strength.
He cannot yet take physical form...
...but his spirit has lost none of its potency.
Concealed within his fortress, the Lord of Mordor sees all.
His gaze pierces cloud, shadow, earth and flesh.
You know of what I speak, Gandalf.
A Great Eye, lidless, wreathed in flame.
The Eye of Sauron.
He is gathering all evil to him.
Very soon, he'll have summoned an army...
...great enough for an assault upon Middle-earth.
You know this?
How?
I have seen it.
A palantir is a dangerous tool, Saruman.
Why?
Why should we fear to use it?
They are not all accounted for, the lost Seeing-stones.
We do not know who else may be watching.
The hour is later than you think.
Sauron's forces are already moving.
The Nine have left Minas Morgul.
The Nine?
They crossed the River Isen on Midsummer's Eve...
...disguised as riders in black.
- They've reached the Shire? - They will find the Ring.
And kill the one who carries it.
Frodo!
You did not seriously think that a Hobbit could contend with the will of Sauron?
There are none who can.
Against the power of Mordor...
...there can be no victory.
We must join with him, Gandalf.
We must join with Sauron.
It would be wise, my friend.
Tell me...
...friend...
...when did Saruman the Wise abandon reason for madness?
I gave you the chance...
...of aiding me willingly...
...but you have elected the way of pain!
Mr. Frodo?
Frodo? Frodo!
- I thought I'd lost you. - What are you talking about?
- It's just something Gandalf said. - What did he say?
"Don't you lose him, Samwise Gamgee." And I don't mean to.
Sam, we're still in the Shire. What could possibly happen?
Frodo.
- Merry, it's Frodo Baggins. - Hello, Frodo.
Get off him.
Come on, Frodo.
What's the meaning of this?
You've been into Farmer Maggot's crop!
You get back here!
Get out of my field!
You'll know the devil if I catch up with you!
I don't know why he's so upset. It's only a couple of carrots.
And some cabbages.
And those three bags of potatoes that we lifted last week.
- And then the mushrooms the week before. - Yes, Pippin. My point is...
...he's clearly overreacting.
Run!
Oh, that was close.
I think I've broken something.
Trust a Brandybuck and a Took!
What? That was just a detour. A short cut.
- Short cut to what? - Mushrooms!
That's mine.
That's nice, Merry.
Here's a nice one, Sam.
I think we should get off the road.
Get off the road!
Quick!
Be quiet!
What was that?
Anything?
Nothing.
What is going on?
That Black Rider was looking for something. Or someone.
Frodo?
Get down!
I have to leave the Shire.
Sam and I must get to Bree.
Right.
Bucklebury Ferry. Follow me.
Run!
This way! Follow me!
Get the rope, Sam!
Frodo!
Run, Frodo!
- Go! - Hurry!
Frodo, come on!
- Come on! Faster! - Jump!
- How far to the nearest crossing? - The Brandywine Bridge. 20 miles.
Come on.
- What do you want? - We're heading for the Prancing Pony.
Hobbits. Four Hobbits!
What's more, out of the Shire by your talk. What business brings you to Bree?
We wish to stay at the inn. Our business is our own.
All right, young sir. I meant no offense.
It's my job to ask questions after nightfall.
There's talk of strange folk abroad.
Can't be too careful.
Out of the way! Watch where you're walking.
Excuse me.
Good evening, little masters. What can I do for you?
If you're seeking accommodation, we got some cozy Hobbit-sized rooms available.
Always proud to cater to the Little Folk, Mister...?
Underhill. My name's Underhill.
- Underhill, yes. - We're friends of Gandalf the Grey.
- Can you tell him we've arrived? - Gandalf?
Gandalf.
Oh, yes...
...I remember. Elderly chap.
Big grey beard, pointy hat.
Not seen him for six months.
What do we do now?
Sam...
...he'll be here. He'll come.
Get out of my way!
What's that?
This, my friend, is a pint.
It comes in pints?
- I'm getting one. - You got a whole half already!
That fellow's done nothing but stare at you since we arrived.
Excuse me.
That Man in the corner. Who is he?
He's one of them Rangers. They're dangerous folk, wandering the Wilds.
What his right name is, I've never heard, but around here he's known as Strider.
Strider.
Baggins.
Baggins? Sure, I know a Baggins.
He's over there. Frodo Baggins.
He's my second cousin, once removed on his mother's side...
...and my third cousin, twice removed....
- Pippin! - Steady on, Frodo.
You cannot hide.
I see you.
There is no life...
...in the void.
Only...
...death.
You draw far too much attention to yourself, "Mr. Underhill."
What do you want?
A little more caution from you. That is no trinket you carry.
- I carry nothing. - Indeed.
I can avoid being seen if I wish...
...but to disappear entirely, that is a rare gift.
- Who are you? - Are you frightened?
Yes.
Not nearly frightened enough. I know what hunts you.
Let him go! Or I'll have you, Longshanks.
You have a stout heart, little Hobbit. But that will not save you.
You can no longer wait for the wizard, Frodo.
They're coming.
What are they?
They were once Men.
Great kings of Men.
Then Sauron the Deceiver gave to them nine rings of power.
Blinded by their greed, they took them without question.
One by one, falling into darkness.
Now they are slaves to his will.
They are the Nazgul.
Ringwraiths. Neither living nor dead.
At all times they feel...
...the presence of the Ring...
...drawn to the power of the One. They will never stop hunting you.
- Where are you taking us? - Into the Wild.
How do we know this Strider is a friend of Gandalf?
I think a servant of the enemy would look fairer...
- ...and feel fouler. - He's foul enough.
We have no choice but to trust him.
- But where is he leading us? - To Rivendell, Master Gamgee.
- To the house of Elrond. - Did you hear that? Rivendell.
We're going to see the Elves.
- Gentlemen, we do not stop till nightfall. - What about breakfast?
- You've already had it. - We've had one, yes.
What about second breakfast?
Don't think he knows about second breakfast, Pip.
What about elevenses? Luncheon? Afternoon tea? Dinner? Supper?
- He knows about them, doesn't he? - I wouldn't count on it.
Pippin!
What do they eat when they can't get Hobbit?
Who is she?
This woman you sing of.
'Tis the lady of Luthien.
The Elf-maiden who gave her love to Beren, a mortal.
What happened to her?
She died.
Get some sleep, Frodo.
The power of Isengard is at your command...
...Sauron, Lord of the Earth.
Build me an army worthy of Mordor.
What orders from Mordor, my lord? What does the Eye command?
We have work to do.
The trees are strong, my lord. Their roots go deep.
Rip them all down.
This was the great watchtower of Amon Sul.
We shall rest here tonight.
These are for you. Keep them close.
I'm going to have a look around.
Stay here.
My tomato's burst.
Could I have some bacon?
Want a tomato, Sam?
- What are you doing?! - Tomatoes, sausages, nice crispy bacon.
- We saved some for you, Mr. Frodo. - Put it out, you fools!
- Put it out! - That's nice! Ash on my tomatoes!
Go!
Back, you devils!
Frodo!
Oh, Sam.
Strider!
- Help him, Strider. - He's been stabbed by a Morgul blade.
This is beyond my skill to heal. He needs Elvish medicine.
Hurry!
We're six days from Rivendell! He'll never make it!
Hold on, Frodo.
Gandalf!
Look, Frodo. It's Mr. Bilbo's trolls.
Mr. Frodo? He's going cold.
Is he going to die?
He's passing into the Shadow World. He'll soon become a Wraith like them.
- They're close. - Sam, do you know the Athelas plant?
- Athelas? - Kingsfoil.
Kingsfoil, aye, it's a weed.
It may help to slow the poisoning. Hurry!
What's this? A Ranger caught off his guard?
Frodo.
I am Arwen - I've come to help you.
Hear my voice...
Come back to the light.
Who is she?
Frodo.
- She's an Elf. - He's fading.
He's not going to last.
We must get him to my father.
- I've been looking for you for two days. - Where are you taking him?
There are five Wraiths behind you. Where the other four are, I do not know.
Stay with the Hobbits - I'll send horses for you.
I'm the faster rider - I'll take him
The Road is too dangerous.
What are they saying?
If I can get across the river...
...the power of my people will protect him.
I do not fear them.
Arwen...
...ride hard. Don't look back.
What are you doing?! Those Wraiths are still out there!
Give up the halfling, She-Elf.
If you want him, come and claim him.
No. No!
Frodo, no.
Frodo, don't give in.
Not now.
What grace is given me...
...let it pass to him.
Let him be spared.
Save him.
- Where am I? - You are in the house of Elrond.
And it is 10:00 in the morning on October 24th, if you want to know.
- Gandalf! - Yes, I'm here.
And you're lucky to be here too.
A few more hours and you would have been beyond our aid.
But you have some strength in you, my dear Hobbit.
What happened, Gandalf?
- Why didn't you meet us? - I am sorry, Frodo.
I was delayed.
A friendship with Saruman is not lightly thrown aside.
One ill turn deserves another. It is over.
Embrace the power of the Ring...
...or embrace your own destruction!
There is only one Lord of the Ring.
Only one who can bend it to his will.
And he does not share power.
So you have chosen death.
Gandalf? What is it?
Nothing, Frodo.
Frodo!
- Sam. - Bless you, you're awake!
Sam has hardly left your side.
We were that worried about you. Weren't we, Mr. Gandalf?
By the skills of Lord Elrond, you're beginning to mend.
Welcome to Rivendell, Frodo Baggins.
- Bilbo! - Hello, Frodo, my lad.
Bilbo.
"There and Back Again:
A Hobbit's Tale, by Bilbo Baggins."
- This is wonderful. - I meant to go back...
...wander the paths of Mirkwood...
...visit Lake-town...
...see the Lonely Mountain again.
But age, it seems, has finally caught up with me.
I miss the Shire.
I spent all my childhood pretending I was off somewhere else.
Off with you, on one of your adventures.
But my own adventure turned out to be quite different.
I'm not like you, Bilbo.
My dear boy.
- Now, what have I forgotten? - Packed already?
No harm in being prepared.
- I thought you wanted to see the Elves. - I do.
- More than anything. - I did.
It's just....
We did what Gandalf wanted, didn't we?
We got the Ring this far, to Rivendell. And I thought...
...seeing as how you're on the mend, we'd be off soon.
Off home.
You are right, Sam.
We did what we set out to do.
The Ring will be safe in Rivendell.
I am ready to go home.
His strength returns.
That wound will never fully heal. He will carry it the rest of his life.
And yet to have come so far still bearing the Ring...
...the Hobbit has shown extraordinary resilience to its evil.
It is a burden he should never have had to bear.
- We can ask no more of Frodo. - Gandalf, the enemy is moving.
Sauron's forces are massing in the East. His Eye is fixed on Rivendell.
And Saruman, you tell me, has betrayed us.
Our list of allies grows thin.
His treachery runs deeper than you know.
By foul craft, Saruman has crossed Orcs with Goblin-men.
He's breeding an army in the caverns of Isengard.
An army that can move in sunlight and cover great distance at speed.
Saruman is coming for the Ring.
This evil cannot be concealed by the power of the Elves.
We do not have the strength to fight both Mordor and Isengard!
Gandalf...
...the Ring cannot stay here.
This peril belongs to all Middle-earth.
They must decide now how to end it.
The time of the Elves is over. My people are leaving these shores.
Who will you look to when we've gone? The Dwarves?
They hide in mountains seeking riches. They care not for the troubles of others.
It is in Men that we must place our hope.
Men?
Men are weak. The race of Men is failing.
The blood of Numenor is all but spent, its pride and dignity forgotten.
It is because of Men the Ring survives.
I was there, Gandalf.
I was there 3000 years ago...
...when Isildur took the Ring.
I was there the day the strength of Men failed.
Isildur, hurry! Follow me.
I led Isildur into the heart of Mount Doom...
...where the Ring was forged, the one place it could be destroyed.
Cast it into the fire!
- Destroy it! - No.
Isildur!
It should have ended that day, but evil was allowed to endure.
Isildur kept the Ring. The line of kings is broken.
There's no strength left in the world of Men.
- They're scattered, divided, leaderless. - There is one who could unite them.
One who could reclaim the throne of Gondor.
He turned from that path a long time ago.
He has chosen exile.
You are no Elf.
Men of the South are welcome here.
- Who are you? - I am a friend to Gandalf the Grey.
Then we are here on common purpose...
...friend.
The shards of Narsil.
The blade that cut the Ring from Sauron's hand.
It's still sharp.
But no more than a broken heirloom.
Why do you fear the past?
You are Isildur's heir, not Isildur himself.
You are not bound to his fate.
The same blood flows in my veins.
The same weakness.
Your time will come.
You will face the same evil. And you will defeat it.
The Shadow does not hold sway yet.
Not over you... not over me.
Do you remember when we first met?
I thought I had strayed into a dream.
Long years have passed.
You did not have the cares you carry now.
Do you remember what I told you?
You said you'd bind yourself to me...
...forsaking the immortal life of your people.
And to that I hold.
I would rather share one lifetime with you...
...than face all the Ages of this world alone.
I choose a mortal life.
- You cannot give me this. - It is mine to give to whom I will...
...like my heart.
Strangers from distant lands, friends of old...
...you've been summoned here to answer the threat of Mordor.
Middle-earth stands upon the brink of destruction. None can escape it.
You will unite, or you will fall.
Each race is bound to this fate, this one doom.
Bring forth the Ring, Frodo.
So it is true.
In a dream...
...I saw the eastern sky grow dark...
...but in the West a pale light lingered.
A voice was crying:
"Your doom is near at hand.
Isildur's Bane is found."
Isildur's Bane.
Boromir!
Never before has any voice uttered the words of that tongue here in Imladris.
I do not ask your pardon, Master Elrond...
...for the Black Speech of Mordor...
...may yet be heard...
...in every corner of the West!
The Ring is altogether evil.
It is a gift.
A gift to the foes of Mordor.
Why not use this Ring?
Long has my father, the Steward of Gondor...
...kept the forces of Mordor at bay. By the blood of our people...
...are your lands kept safe.
Give Gondor the weapon of the enemy. Let us use it against him.
You cannot wield it. None of us can.
The One Ring answers to Sauron alone. It has no other master.
And what would a Ranger know of this matter?
This is no mere Ranger.
He is Aragorn, son of Arathorn.
You owe him your allegiance.
Aragorn.
This is Isildur's heir?
And heir to the throne of Gondor.
Sit down, Legolas.
Gondor has no king.
Gondor needs no king.
Aragorn is right. We cannot use it.
You have only one choice.
The Ring must be destroyed.
What are we waiting for?
The Ring cannot be destroyed, Gimli, son of Gloin...
...by any craft that we here possess.
The Ring was made in the fires of Mount Doom.
Only there can it be unmade.
It must be taken deep into Mordor...
...and cast back into the fiery chasm from whence it came.
One of you...
...must do this.
One does not simply walk into Mordor.
Its Black Gates are guarded by more than just Orcs.
There is evil there that does not sleep.
The Great Eye is ever-watchful.
It is a barren wasteland...
...riddled with fire, and ash and dust.
The very air you breathe is a poisonous fume.
Not with 10,000 men could you do this. It is folly.
Have you heard nothing Lord Elrond has said? The Ring must be destroyed.
And I suppose you think you are the one to do it!
And if we fail, what then? What happens when Sauron takes back what is his?
I will be dead before I see the Ring in the hands of an Elf!
Never trust an Elf!
Do you not understand? While you bicker amongst yourselves, Sauron's power grows!
None can escape it! You'll all be destroyed!
I will take it.
I will take the Ring to Mordor.
Though...
...I do not know the way.
I will help you bear this burden, Frodo Baggins...
...as long as it is yours to bear.
If by my life or death I can protect you...
...I will.
You have my sword.
And you have my bow.
And my ax.
You carry the fates of us all, little one.
If this is indeed the will of the Council...
...then Gondor will see it done.
- Frodo's not going anywhere without me. - It is hardly possible to separate you...
...even when he is summoned to a secret Council and you are not.
We're coming too!
You'll have to send us home tied up in a sack to stop us.
Anyway, you need people of intelligence on this sort of...
...mission.
Quest.
Thing.
Well, that rules you out, Pip.
Nine companions.
So be it.
You shall be the Fellowship of the Ring.
Great!
Where are we going?
She wanted to protect her child...
she thought in Rivendell you would be safe.
In her heart, your mother knew you'd be hunted all your life.
That you'd never escape your fate.
The skill of the Elves can reforge the sword of kings...
...but only you have the power to wield it.
I do not want that power.
I have never wanted it.
You are the last of that bloodline. There is no other.
My old sword! Sting.
Here, take it. Take it.
- It's so light. - Yes. Made by the Elves, you know.
The blade glows blue when Orcs are close.
And it's times like that, my lad, when you have to be extra careful.
Here's a pretty thing.
Mithril.
As light as a feather, and as hard as dragon scales.
Let me see you put it on. Come on.
My old ring.
I should very much like...
...to hold it again, one last time.
I'm sorry I brought this upon you, my boy.
I'm sorry that you must carry this burden.
I'm sorry for everything.
The Ring-bearer is setting out on the Quest of Mount Doom.
On you who travel with him, no oath...
...nor bond is laid to go further than you will.
Farewell. Hold to your purpose.
May the blessings of Elves and Men...
...and all Free Folk go with you.
The Fellowship awaits the Ring-bearer.
Mordor, Gandalf, is it left or right?
Left.
We must hold to this course, west of the Misty Mountains, for 40 days.
If our luck holds, the Gap of Rohan will still be open to us.
From there, our road turns east to Mordor.
Two, one, five. Good! Very good.
Move your feet.
- You look good, Pippin. - Thanks.
Faster!
If anyone was to ask for my opinion, which I note they're not...
...I'd say we were taking the long way 'round.
Gandalf, we could pass through the Mines of Moria.
My cousin Balin would give us a royal welcome.
No, I would not take the road through Moria unless I had no other choice.
Sorry!
Get him!
- For the Shire! - Hold him. Hold him down, Merry!
Gentlemen, that's enough.
You've got my arm! You've got my arm!
- What is that? - Nothing. It's just a wisp of cloud.
It's moving fast.
Against the wind.
- Crebain from Dunland! - Hide!
- Hurry! - Take cover!
Spies of Saruman.
The passage south is being watched.
We must take the Pass of Caradhras.
Frodo!
Boromir.
It is a strange fate that we should suffer so much fear and doubt...
...over so small a thing.
Such a little thing.
Boromir!
Give the Ring to Frodo.
As you wish.
I care not.
So, Gandalf, you try to lead them over Caradhras.
And if that fails, where then will you go?
If the mountain defeats you...
...will you risk a more dangerous road?
There is a fell voice on the air.
It's Saruman!
He's trying to bring down the mountain! Gandalf, we must turn back!
No!
We must get off the mountain!
Make for the Gap of Rohan, and take the west road to my city!
The Gap of Rohan takes us too close to Isengard!
We cannot pass over a mountain. Let us go under it.
Let us go through the Mines of Moria.
Moria. You fear to go into those mines.
The Dwarves delved too greedily and too deep.
You know what they awoke in the darkness of Khazad-dum:
Shadow and flame.
Let the Ring-bearer decide.
We cannot stay here!
This will be the death of the Hobbits.
Frodo?
We will go through the mines.
So be it.
Frodo, come and help an old man.
How is your shoulder?
- Better than it was. - And the Ring?
You feel its power growing, don't you?
I've felt it too. You must be careful now.
Evil will be drawn to you from outside the Fellowship.
And, I fear, from within.
- Who then do I trust? - You must trust yourself.
Trust your own strengths.
- What do you mean? - There are many powers in this world...
...for good or for evil.
Some are greater than I am.
And against some I have not yet been tested.
The walls...
...of Moria.
Dwarf doors are invisible when closed.
Yes, Gimli, their own masters cannot find them if their secrets are forgotten.
Why doesn't that surprise me?
Well, let's see.
Ithildin.
It mirrors only starlight and moonlight.
It reads, "The Doors of Durin, Lord of Moria.
- Speak, friend, and enter." - What do you suppose that means?
It's simple. If you are a friend, you speak the password and the doors will open.
Nothing's happening.
I once knew every spell in all the tongues of Elves...
...Men and Orcs.
What are you going to do, then?
Knock your head against these doors, Peregrin Took!
And if that does not shatter them...
...and I am allowed a little peace from foolish questions...
...I will try to find the opening words.
Mines are no place for a pony.
- Even one so brave as Bill. - Bye-bye, Bill.
Go on, Bill. Go on.
Don't worry, Sam, he knows the way home.
Do not disturb the water.
Oh, it's useless.
It's a riddle.
"Speak 'friend' and enter."
What's the Elvish word for "friend"?
Mellon.
Soon, Master Elf, you will enjoy the fabled hospitality of the Dwarves.
Roaring fires, malt beer, ripe meat off the bone!
This, my friend, is the home of my cousin Balin.
And they call it a mine.
A mine!
This is no mine. It's a tomb.
No....
No!
Goblins.
We make for the Gap of Rohan. We should never have come here.
Now, get out of here. Get out!
- Frodo! - Help!
Strider!
- Help! - Get off him!
Aragorn!
Frodo!
Into the mines!
- Legolas! - Into the cave!
Run!
We now have but one choice.
We must face the long dark of Moria.
Be on your guard.
There are older and fouler things than Orcs...
...in the deep places of the world.
Quietly now. It's a four-day journey to the other side.
Let us hope that our presence may go unnoticed.
The wealth of Moria was not in gold...
...or jewels...
...but mithril.
Bilbo had a shirt of mithril rings that Thorin gave him.
- Oh, that was a kingly gift. - Yes.
I never told him...
...but its worth was greater than the value of the Shire.
Pippin.
I have no memory of this place.
- Are we lost? - No.
- I think we are. - Gandalf's thinking.
- Merry? - What?
I'm hungry.
- There's something down there. - It's Gollum.
- Gollum? - He's been following us for three days.
- He escaped the dungeons of Barad-dur? - Escaped...
...or was set loose.
Now the Ring has brought him here.
He will never be rid of his need for it.
He hates and loves the Ring, as he hates and loves himself.
Smeagol's life is a sad story.
Yes, Smeagol he was once called. Before the Ring found him.
Before it drove him mad.
It's a pity Bilbo didn't kill him when he had the chance.
Pity?
It is pity that stayed Bilbo's hand.
Many that live deserve death. Some that die deserve life.
Can you give it to them, Frodo?
Do not be too eager to deal out death and judgment.
Even the very wise cannot see all ends.
My heart tells me that Gollum has some part to play yet, for good or ill...
...before this is over.
The pity of Bilbo may rule the fate of many.
I wish the Ring had never come to me.
I wish none of this had happened.
So do all who live to see such times. But that is not for them to decide.
All we have to decide is what to do with the time that is given to us.
There are other forces at work in this world, Frodo, besides the will of evil.
Bilbo was meant to find the Ring.
In which case, you also were meant to have it.
And that is an encouraging thought.
It's that way.
- He's remembered. - No.
But the air doesn't smell so foul down here.
If in doubt, Meriadoc, always follow your nose.
Let me risk a little more light.
Behold...
...the great realm and Dwarf-city of Dwarrowdelf.
There's an eye opener, and no mistake.
Gimli!
No!
Oh, no.
No.
"Here lies Balin...
...son of Fundin...
...Lord of Moria."
He is dead, then.
It's as I feared.
We must move on. We cannot linger.
"They have taken the bridge and the second hall.
We have barred the gates...
...but cannot hold them for long.
The ground shakes.
Drums...
...drums in the deep.
We cannot get out.
A Shadow moves in the dark.
They are coming."
Fool of a Took!
Throw yourself in next time, and rid us of your stupidity.
Frodo!
Orcs.
Get back! Stay close to Gandalf!
They have a cave-troll.
Let them come!
There is one Dwarf yet in Moria who still draws breath.
I think I'm getting the hang of this.
Frodo!
Aragorn! Aragorn!
Oh, no.
He's alive.
I'm all right. I'm not hurt.
You should be dead.
That spear would have skewered a wild boar.
I think there's more to this Hobbit than meets the eye.
Mithril.
You are full of surprises, Master Baggins.
To the Bridge of Khazad-dum!
This way!
What is this new devilry?
A Balrog.
A demon of the ancient world.
This foe is beyond any of you.
Run!
Quickly!
Gandalf.
Lead them on, Aragorn.
The bridge is near.
Do as I say! Swords are no more use here.
Gandalf!
Merry! Pippin!
Sam!
Nobody tosses a Dwarf.
Not the beard!
Steady.
Hold on!
Hang on!
Lean forward!
Steady.
Come on!
Now!
Over the bridge!
Fly!
You cannot pass!
Gandalf!
I am a servant of the Secret Fire, wielder of the flame of Anor.
The dark fire will not avail you, flame of Udun!
Go back to the Shadow.
You shall not pass!
- No! No! - Gandalf!
Fly, you fools!
No!
Aragorn!
Legolas, get them up.
Give them a moment, for pity's sake!
By nightfall, these hills will be swarming with Orcs.
We must reach the woods of Lothlorien.
Come, Boromir. Legolas. Gimli, get them up.
On your feet, Sam.
Frodo?
Frodo!
Stay close, young Hobbits!
They say that a great sorceress lives in these woods.
An Elf-witch...
...of terrible power.
All who look upon her...
...fall under her spell.
Frodo!
And are never seen again.
Your coming to us is as the footsteps of doom.
You bring great evil here, Ring-bearer.
Mr. Frodo?
Well, here's one Dwarf she won't ensnare so easily.
I have the eyes of a hawk and the ears of a fox.
The Dwarf breathes so loud, we could have shot him in the dark.
Welcome Legolas, son of Thranduil.
Our Fellowship stands in your debt.
Aragorn of the Dunedain...
you are known to us.
So much for the legendary courtesy of the Elves!
Speak words we can all understand!
We have not had dealings with the Dwarves since the Dark Days.
And you know what this Dwarf says to that?
That was not so courteous.
You bring great evil with you.
You can go no further.
Gandalf's death was not in vain.
Nor would he have you give up hope.
You carry a heavy burden, Frodo.
Don't carry the weight of the dead.
You will follow me.
Caras Galadhon.
The heart of Elvendom on earth.
Realm of the Lord Celeborn and of Galadriel, Lady of Light.
The enemy knows you have entered here.
What hope you had in secrecy is now gone.
Eight there are here, yet nine there were set out from Rivendell.
Tell me, where is Gandalf?
For I much desire to speak with him.
I can no longer see him from afar.
Gandalf the Grey did not pass the borders of this land.
He has fallen into Shadow.
He was taken by both Shadow and flame.
A Balrog of Morgoth.
For we went needlessly into the net of Moria.
Needless were none of the deeds of Gandalf in life.
We do not yet know his full purpose.
Do not let the great emptiness of Khazad-dum fill your heart...
...Gimli, son of Gloin.
For the world has grown full of peril...
...and in all lands...
...love is now mingled with grief.
What now becomes of this Fellowship?
Without Gandalf, hope is lost.
The quest stands upon the edge of a knife.
Stray but a little and it will fail...
...to the ruin of all.
Yet hope remains while the Company is true.
Do not let your hearts be troubled. Go now and rest...
...for you are weary with sorrow and much toil.
Tonight, you will sleep....
Welcome, Frodo of the Shire...
...one who has seen the Eye!
A lament for Gandalf.
What do they say about him?
I have not the heart to tell you.
For me, the grief is still too near.
I bet they don't mention his fireworks.
There should be a verse about them.
The finest rockets ever seen
They burst in stars of blue and green
Or after thunder, silver showers
Came falling like a rain of flowers
Oh, that doesn't do them justice by a long road.
Take some rest.
These borders are well-protected.
I will find no rest here.
I heard her voice inside my head.
She spoke of my father and the fall of Gondor.
She said to me, "Even now there is hope left."
But I cannot see it.
It is long since we had any hope.
My father is a noble man.
But his rule is failing...
...and our people lose faith.
He looks to me to make things right, and I would do it.
I would see the glory of Gondor restored.
Have you ever seen it, Aragorn?
The White Tower of Ecthelion.
Glimmering like a spike of pearl and silver.
Its banners caught high in the morning breeze.
Have you ever been called home...
...by the clear ringing of silver trumpets?
I have seen the White City...
...long ago.
One day, our paths will lead us there.
And the tower guard shall take up the call:
"The Lords of Gondor have returned."
Will you look into the mirror?
What will I see?
Even the wisest cannot tell.
For the mirror...
...shows many things.
Things that were...
...things that are...
...and some things...
...that have not yet come to pass.
I know what it is you saw.
For it is also in my mind.
It is what will come to pass ifyou should fail.
The Fellowship is breaking. It is already begun.
He will try to take the Ring.
You know of whom I speak.
One by one, it will destroy them all.
If you ask it of me...
...I will give you the One Ring.
You offer it to me freely.
I do not deny that my heart has greatly desired this.
In place of a Dark Lord, you would have a queen...
...not dark but beautiful, and terrible as the dawn!
Treacherous as the sea!
Stronger than the foundations of the earth!
All shall love me...
...and despair.
I pass the test. I will diminish...
...and go into the West...
- ...and remain Galadriel. - I cannot do this alone.
You are a Ring-bearer, Frodo. To bear a Ring of Power...
...is to be alone.
This is Nenya, the Ring of Adamant.
And I am its keeper.
This task was appointed to you.
And if you do not find a way...
...no one will.
Then I know what I must do.
It's just...
...I'm afraid to do it.
Even the smallest person can change the course of the future.
Do you know how the Orcs first came into being?
They were Elves once.
Taken by the Dark Powers...
...tortured and mutilated.
A ruined and terrible form of life.
And now...
...perfected.
My fighting Uruk-hai...
...whom do you serve?
Saruman!
Hunt them down. Do not stop until they are found.
You do not know pain. You do not know fear.
You will taste Man-flesh!
One of the halflings carries something of great value.
Bring them to me alive and unspoiled.
Kill the others.
Never before have we clad strangers in the garb of our own people.
May these cloaks help shield you from unfriendly eyes.
Lembas.
Elvish waybread.
One small bite is enough to fill the stomach of a grown man.
How many did you eat?
Four.
Every league you travel south, the danger will increase.
Mordor Orcs now hold the eastern shore of the Anduin.
Nor will you find safety on the western bank.
Strange creatures bearing the White Hand have been seen on our borders.
Seldom do Orcs journey in the open under the sun, yet these have done so.
You are being tracked.
By river you have the chance of outrunning the enemy to the Falls of Rauros.
My gift for you, Legolas, is a bow of the Galadhrim.
Worthy of the skill of our woodland kin.
These are the daggers of the Noldorin.
They have already seen service in war.
Do not fear, young Peregrin Took.
You will find your courage.
And for you, Samwise Gamgee...
...Elven rope made of hithlain.
Thank you, my lady.
Have you run out of those nice, shiny daggers?
And what gift would a dwarf ask of the Elves?
Nothing.
Except to look upon the lady of the Galadhrim one last time...
...for she is more fair than all the jewels beneath the earth.
Actually....
There was one thing.
No, no, I couldn't. It's quite impossible.
Stupid to ask.
I have nothing greater to give...
...than the gift you already bear.
For her love,
I fear the grace of Arwen Evenstar will diminish.
I would have her leave these shores,
and be with her people.
I would have her take the ship to Valinor.
That choice is yet before her.
You have your own choice to make, Aragorn.
To rise above the height of all your fathers since the days of Elendil...
...or to fall into darkness with all that is left of your kin.
Farewell.
There is much you have yet to do.
We shall not meet again...
Elessar.
Farewell, Frodo Baggins.
I give you the light of Earendil...
...our most beloved star.
May it be a light for you in dark places...
...when all other lights go out.
I have taken my worst wound at this parting...
...having looked my last upon that which is fairest.
Henceforth I will call nothing fair unless it be her gift to me.
What was her gift?
I asked her for one hair from her golden head.
She gave me three.
Gollum. He has tracked us since Moria.
I had hoped we would lose him on the river.
But he's too clever a waterman.
And if he alerts the enemy to our whereabouts...
...it will make the crossing even more dangerous.
Have some food, Mr. Frodo.
- No, Sam. - You haven't eaten anything all day.
You're not sleeping, neither. Don't think I haven't noticed.
- Mr. Frodo-- - I'm all right.
But you're not.
I'm here to help you.
I promised Gandalf that I would.
You can't help me, Sam.
Not this time.
Get some sleep.
Minas Tirith is the safer road.
You know that. From there we can regroup.
Strike out for Mordor from a place of strength.
There is no strength in Gondor that can avail us.
You were quick enough to trust the Elves.
Have you so little faith in your own people?
Yes, there is weakness. There is frailty.
But there is courage also, and honor to be found in Men.
But you will not see that.
You are afraid!
All your life, you have hidden in the shadows.
Scared of who you are, of what you are.
I will not lead the Ring within a hundred leagues of your city.
Frodo.
The Argonath.
Long have I desired to look upon the kings of old.
My kin.
We cross the lake at nightfall.
Hide the boats and continue on foot.
- We approach Mordor from the North. - Oh, yes?
Just a simple matter of finding our way through Emyn Muil...
...an impassable labyrinth of razor-sharp rocks.
And after that, it gets even better.
Festering, stinking marshland as far as the eye can see.
That is our road.
I suggest you take some rest and recover your strength, Master Dwarf.
Recover my--
- We should leave now. - No.
Orcs patrol the eastern shore. We must wait for cover of darkness.
It is not the eastern shore that worries me.
A shadow and a threat has been growing in my mind.
Something draws near. I can feel it.
Recover strength? Pay no heed to that, young Hobbit.
Where's Frodo?
None of us should wander alone.
You, least of all.
So much depends on you.
Frodo?
I know why you seek solitude.
You suffer. I see it day by day.
You sure you do not suffer needlessly?
There are other ways, Frodo.
- Other paths that we might take. - I know what you would say.
It would seem like wisdom but for the warning in my heart.
Warning? Against what?
We're all afraid, Frodo.
But to let that fear drive us, to destroy what hope we have...
- ...don't you see that is madness? - There is no other way.
I ask only for the strength to defend my people!
- If you would but lend me the Ring. - No.
- Why do you recoil? I am no thief. - You are not yourself.
What chance do you think you have?
They will find you. They will take the Ring.
And you will beg for death before the end!
You fool!
It is not yours, save by unhappy chance! It could have been mine.
It should be mine! Give it to me!
- Give it to me! - No!
- Give it to me! - No.
I see your mind.
You will take the Ring to Sauron!
You will betray us!
You'll go to your death, and the death of us all!
Curse you! Curse you and all the halflings!
Frodo?
Frodo.
What have I done?
Please, Frodo.
Frodo, I'm sorry!
Frodo?
- It has taken Boromir. - Where is the Ring?
Stay away!
Frodo!
- I swore to protect you. - Can you protect me from yourself?
Would you destroy it?
Aragorn.
Elessar.
I would have gone with you to the end.
Into the very fires of Mordor.
I know.
Look after the others. Especially Sam. He will not understand.
Go, Frodo!
Run.
Run!
Mr. Frodo!
Find the halfling!
Elendil!
Aragorn, go!
Frodo!
Hide here. Quick!
Come on!
What's he doing?
He's leaving.
- No! - Pippin!
Run, Frodo. Go on!
- Hey! Hey, you! - Over here!
- Over here! - This way!
- It's working! - I know it's working! Run!
- The horn of Gondor. - Boromir.
Run!
No.
- They took the little ones. - Hold still.
Frodo. Where is Frodo?
I let Frodo go.
Then you did what I could not.
I tried to take the Ring from him.
- The Ring is beyond our reach now. - Forgive me.
I did not see it.
- I have failed you all. - No, Boromir.
You fought bravely.
You have kept your honor.
Leave it.
It is over.
The world of Men will fall. And all will come to darkness...
...and my city to ruin.
I do not know what strength is in my blood...
...but I swear to you, I will not let the White City fall...
...nor our people fail.
Our people.
I would have followed you, my brother.
My captain.
My king.
Be at peace...
...son of Gondor.
They will look for his coming from the White Tower.
But he will not return.
Frodo!
I wish the Ring had never come to me.
I wish none of this had happened.
So do all who live to see such times...
...but that is not for them to decide.
All you have to decide...
...is what to do with the time that is given to you.
Frodo, no!
Frodo!
- Mr. Frodo! - No, Sam.
Go back, Sam!
- I'm going to Mordor alone. - Of course you are.
And I'm coming with you!
You can't swim!
Sam!
I made a promise, Mr. Frodo.
A promise: "Don't you leave him, Samwise Gamgee."
And I don't mean to.
I don't mean to.
Sam.
Come on.
Hurry! Frodo and Sam have reached the eastern shore.
- You mean not to follow them. - Frodo's fate is no longer in our hands.
Then it has all been in vain. The Fellowship has failed.
Not if we hold true to each other.
We will not abandon Merry and Pippin to torment and death.
Not while we have strength left. Leave all that can be spared behind.
We travel light.
Let us hunt some Orc.
Yes!
Mordor.
I hope the others find a safer road.
Strider will look after them.
I don't suppose we'll ever see them again.
We may yet, Mr. Frodo.
We may.
Sam...
...I'm glad you are with me.